梅森·迪克逊又一次迅速地击倒对手  就像例行公事
Yet another quick knockout for Mason Dixon, almost perfunctory.
观众们都流露出了不满的情绪
The fans let him know how they feel about it.
叫妇女和儿童躲起来吧  情况就快失控了
Hide the women and children. This could get ugly.
面对最后致命的一击  观众难掩愤怒
This crowd does nothing to hide its anger over this latest debacle.
拳迷们近乎疯狂了  他们好像都在怪罪拳王迪克逊
The fans are mad as hell. They don't want to take it anymore.
拖垮了重量级拳赛  甚至是整个拳坛
They seem to be blaming Dixon, a good fighter, for the decline...
大家都对这位叱咤全球的重量级不倒拳王嗤之以鼻
...not only of the heavyweight-division guys, but of the entire sport.
或许这样愤怒的本能反应…
They're actually pelting...
可以逼迫迪克逊挑战有反击能力的强悍对手
...the undefeated heavyweight champion of the world with ice.
如果真的有那种对手的话  其实整个拳坛都希望能有…
Maybe this angry, visceral reaction will pressure Dixon to fight someone...
勇士站出来 挑战迪克逊
...who can fight back for a change. If there' somebody out there.
拳击的真谛是拳手能用他的热情来震撼我们
All of boxing is hoping for a warrior who thrills us with his passion.
时间过得真快
Time goes by too fast.
是么？还不够快
Yeah? Not fast enough.
- 你的孩子本应该来这里  - 那没关系
- Your kid should've been here.  - That's all right.
- 不 怎么没关系  - 他工作有时很忙
- No, it ain't all right.  - The kid gets a little busy sometimes.
来这儿不怎么耽误他事
He don't get that busy.
我们别在这儿谈这个了  好么？你今晚过来坐坐吧？
Let's not talk about it here, okay? You're coming tonight, right?
我有工作  过去的三年  我云游四海
I'm working. I took the tour the last three years.
我知道  但是今天是周年纪念日
I know, but it's the anniversary.
好吧  我来就是了
Fine. You got my word.
我感到很荣幸  谢谢你  我欠你个人情  保利
I appreciate it, thank you. I owe you, Paulie.
罗伯特  怎么回事？你去哪里了？你迟到了
Yo, Robert. What's going on? Where have you been? You're late.
不  我不要听这些解释
No. I don't wanna hear this. Look, your job performance...
听着  你的工作表现真是太糟糕了
...is nowhere near good enough to be pulling this.
我可不管你老爷子是谁  你听明白了吗？
I don't give a damn who your father is. You understand me?
- 好 现在给我工作去  - 好
- All right. Now get out of here.  - Okay.
谢谢  先生
Thank you, sir.
罗伯特
Yo, Robert. Yo.
- 嘿 洛奇  - 嘿
- Hey, Rocky.  - Hey.
- 嘿 你好吗？- 嘿
- Hey, how you doing?  - Hey.
怎么了  拳王？
What's up, champ?
- 你不通知我就来找我  - 我知道
- You caught me off guard.  - I know.
我想在你忙碌之前来找你
I wanted to catch you before you got busy.
对  上面是蛮忙碌的
Yeah, it gets busy up there.
- 最近好吗？- 很好
- So how you doing? Yeah?  - Real good. Yeah.
- 洛奇！- 嗯 你好
- Yo, Rock!  - Yeah, how you doing?
是啊  真的很好
Yeah, real good.
听着  咱们出去喝杯咖啡吧？
Listen, you wanna go out and get some coffee?
我要迟到了  以后吧
I'm kind of behind. Maybe later?
嗯  那好吧  今晚你应该来餐馆
Yeah. That'd be great. You ought to come by the restaurant tonight.
我可以专门为你准备些吃的
I can have something made special for you.
今晚不行  我打算和一些朋友聚聚
Tonight I can't. I got plans. A few of the guys get together.
- 我做错什么了吗？- 什么意思？
- Did I do something wrong?  - What do you mean?
我也不知道确切指什么
Well, I don't know exactly what I mean...
但我总觉得当我来这里时  你总觉得不太舒服
...but I just think, like, when I come here, you don't feel so comfortable.
当然我也不想那样的
And I certainly don't wanna do that.
- 这么说吧 你给我留下了很大的阴影  - 阴影？
- Well, you throw a big shadow.  - A big shadow?
你在下面干不出任何事的  罗伯特
You're not gonna get anything done down here, Robert.
如果你不为我介绍  那我自己来吧  威廉·汤米尔森
Well, if you're not gonna introduce me, I will. Hi, I'm William Tomilson.
- 你好  - 你的儿子为我工作
- How you doing?  - Your son works for me.
- 这是份好工作  - 是啊
- It's a good job.  - Yeah.
我和罗伯特提过很多次  很想见见你
I've told Robert about 20 times that I wanted to meet you.
你真忙啊  那样很充实
You're pretty busy, which isn't a bad thing.
- 我是挺忙的  - 合张照吧？
- I get a little tied up.  - Grab a shot, will you?
下次不一定有机会了  老兵们应该在一起
I may not get this chance again. Old warhorses have to stick together.
- 老骨头了 是啊  - 我会告诉你
- The old horses, yeah.  - I'll tell you.
- 好时光是留不住的  - 这样会让你受欢迎的
- Good thing it's not your left.  - This makes you popular with people.
- 一 二 三  - 最终我们还是见面了
- One, two, three.  - Finally, we get to meet.
我得走了  很高兴能和你面对面
I gotta get going. It was nice to meet you face to face.
你多保重  罗伯特  回头见
You take care of yourself. Robert, I'll see you later.
我得走了  我改变今晚的计划了
I gotta get going. I'll change my plans for tonight.
那太好了  我期待你来
That'd be great. I'm looking forward to it.
- 多保重  - 好的
- How you doing?  - Okay.
- 嗯  - 好的
- Okay.  - All right.
还有别为那些数字抓狂
And do not let those numbers drive you crazy.
- 太迟了  - 用个橡皮擦 把它们全擦干净
- Too late.  - Use an eraser, get rid of all of them.
- 洛奇  - 嘿 朋友们
- Yo, Rock.  - Hey, guys.
- 嘿 洛奇  - 嘿 你好吗？
- Hey, Rock.  - Hey, how you doing?
给
There you go.
这个来十斤  你先保管着
It'll be about 10 tenths. You guys take care, okay? You got it.
过会儿我来买些这个
I'll try a few of these later on.
- 很适合烘烤  - 多少钱？
- It's good for baking.  - How much...?
- 哟 保罗 多少钱？- 58 块 4  先生
- Yo, Paul, what's the cost?  - 58.40, sir.
好  钱拿去  我相信你
All right, take it out of that. I trust you.
- 你好吗？- 你真是太慷慨了
- How you doing?  - You're too generous.
没什么
Not a problem.
朋友们  你们好吗？
How you guys doing?
都在忙什么  伊莎贝尔？
How we doing, Isabel?
都忙着  除了那个在读《圣经》的累赘
Okay, except for the freebie reading the Bible.
- 他没事  - 仅仅因为你曾战胜过他
- He's okay.  - Just because you fought him...
并不代表你要养着他  他看起来不像个拳手
...don't mean you gotta feed him. He doesn't look like a fighter.
斯柏德·里克挺能打的
Spider Rico could hit.
- 你肚子怎么样？- 还好
- Listen, how's your stomach?  - It's okay.
如果你坚持在肚子上抹橄榄油
If you keep rubbing olive oil on your stomach...
你的孩子一出身就会非常强壮
...your kid's gonna be born very strong.
- 好吧 洛奇 随便你怎么说吧  - 不 这是真的
- Okay, Rocky. Whatever you say.  - No, really.
- 你还好吧 斯柏德？- 上帝保佑你 洛奇
- Yo, how you doing, Spider?  - God bless you, Rocky.
谢谢
Thanks.
伙计们  你们好吗？
How you guys doing?
何塞  今晚我儿子要来  你能为他做点特别的吗？
Jose, can you make something special for my kid who's coming tonight?
没问题
No problemo.
好  我很感激
Good. I appreciate it.
进进退退  防守  进攻
Back and forth, back and forth, give and take.
然后我像头野兽般冲向他  把他逼向绳角…
And then I went in there like an animal and threw him into the corner...
然后我使出浑身解数  勾拳  勾拳  左勾拳  右勾拳
...and I unloaded everything I had. Hook, hook, hook, left, left, left.
但是科里德  一直凶猛的攻击我的背部
But Creed, he kept busting me back pretty good...
…我开始忍受痛苦煎熬
...and the agony began to pile up.
那时我听到了我有生以来最美好的声音
Then I heard the best sound that I ever heard in my life...
- 回合结束的铃声  - 对 就是这个铃声
- The bell.  - That's right, the bell.
我瘫坐在角落里  从没感受到如此疲倦
I ain't never been so tired, and I'm sitting in my corner.
我试着去想如何熬过最后一个回合…
I'm trying to figure out how to survive the last round...
当米奇靠近我的耳朵  和我说
...when Mickey leans into my ear and says:
"振作起来  狠狠的揍那家伙"
"Come on, get out there and fight this guy hard, you bum.
"你一定是拳王  一定是"  我答道 "如果我可以…"
You gotta be first. You gotta be first." I said, "Yo, Mick, if I could...
- "我一定会"  - "我一定会"
- "I would." ...I would."
当时就是这样
The end.
梅森·迪克逊又一次快速击倒对手  就像例行公事
Yet another quick knockout for Mason Dixon, almost perfunctory.
拳迷们想让他知道他们的感受
The fans let him know how they feel about it.
他们甚至用冰块…
They're actually pelting...
…砸向这位世界  最重量级卫冕拳王
...the undefeated heavyweight champion of the world with ice.
你好  艾黛丽安餐馆  是吗？
Hello, Adriars. Yeah?
告诉他你不能来了？好  我会帮你传达这个口信的
Tell him you can't make it? Yeah, I'll give him the message.
米奇的声音  在我耳边回荡了一遍又一遍
I just kept hearing Mickey's voice in my head over and over again.
我只是倒了下去  之前你知道…
I just dug down, and before you know it...
我们针锋相对… 抱歉
...it was toe to toe and it was... Excuse me.
你儿子说他不能来了  他说他下次再来
Your son said he can't make it. He said he'll take a rain check. Okay?
瞧这些鸟儿
Look at these birds.
这些鸟看起来难道不像糖果吗？会飞的糖果？
Don't these birds look like candy? Flying candy?
嘿  鸟儿  你能载我回家么？
Hey, birdie, you wanna fly me home?
你需要谁送你回家吗？
You need somebody to walk you home?
不需要？
No?
今晚很冷  人生需要多一点的笑声  你觉得呢？
It's a cold night. We need a few laughs in our life. What do you think? Maybe?
也许？也许？
Maybe? Maybe?
好  我们走吧？
Okay. Let' get out of here, okay?
这地方和去年没什么不同
That place ain't changed much from last year.
我们走吧？
Are we done?
嘿  你好吗  米奇？
Hey, how you doing, Mick?
招牌快掉下来了  保利
That sign is falling apart, Paulie.
整个世界都要倒下了  瞧瞧我们
The whole world is falling apart. Look at us.
别疯言疯语了  保利
Don't talk crazy, Paulie.
你知道  我觉得如果在某个地方住得够久  就会融入其中
You know, I think if you live someplace long enough, you are that place.
我不是指的建筑
I ain't no talking building.
走吧  天色不早了  洛奇
Come on, it's getting late, Rocko.
这火车的声音让我头疼
I get a headache from this train.
我记得当时她站在这里…
I remember when she was standing there...
紧张和羞怯  带着一丝微笑
...all nervous and shy, with this little smile.
我所要她做的仅仅是相信我
And all I wanted her to do was trust me.
她做到了
She did.
- 她做到了  - 你有完没完？
- She did.  - You done?
- 我们在这呆多久？- 一会就行
- How long are we staying here?  - Not long.
我很高兴他们把这个溜冰场拆了
Well, I'm glad they tore this ice rink down.
得了吧
Come on.
我说了  我很高兴他们把这拆了
You heard me. I'm happy they tore it apart.
我第一次带你妹妹在冰上散步时  当时我们在那里
First time I walked your sister across this ice, we was over there.
她有些紧张  但其实我也不擅长滑冰
She was nervous, but I wasrt so great on the blades either.
多愚蠢的冰  站在冰面上的人更愚蠢
Ice is stupid. People standing on ice are more stupid.
还有在那里  当时她快要摔倒…
And over there, when she was falling...
我的手抓住了她…
...and my hand grabbed her...
隔着外套我抓着她的手臂  我能感受到
...and I got her arm through that coat, I could feel it.
暖流
Electric.
去年你也是那么说的  洛奇
You said the same thing last year, Rock.
是吗？
Did I?
你最好开发下你的大脑了
So you better develop your brain.
- 你是个左撇子  - 当然
- You're left-handed.  - Absolutely.
快点  洛奇  我们走了
Come on, Rock. Let's go.
走吧  这周围连坐的地方都没有
We're done. There's no place to sit down around here.
没关系
It's all right.
怎么没关系？这好萧条  冻死人了！
It ain't all right! It's depressing and freaking cold!
你怎么了  保利？
What's the matter with you, Paulie?
你生活在过去  洛奇！
You're living backwards, Rocko!
人不能总活在过去  过去并不美好！
Change the channel from yesterday! Yesterday wasrt so great!
- 对我来说是的  - 对我不是！
- It was to me.  - Not to me!
你待她很好  你们有过美好的时光
You treated her good. You had the good times.
我待她不好  我不想回忆这些
I treated her bad. I don't have to think about this.
她一直爱你  保利
She always loved you, Paulie.
对不起  洛奇  我已经不想再回忆这些了
Sorry, Rocko, I can't do this no more.
有什么需要帮忙的？
Can I help you?
不  不  很久以前我常来这里
No, no, I used to come down to this place a long time ago.
我只是四处看看  没什么事
I was just looking around. No big deal.
要喝的吗？
Can I get you a drink?
- 好吧 来一小瓶啤酒  - 好
- All right. Maybe just a short beer.  - Okay.
去  去啊
Go. Go on.
对啊  去呀  让他买单
Yeah, go on. Get him to buy a round.
让他买单  去啊
Get him to buy a round. Go.
让那家伙买单  他有钱
Get him to... He's got it. He's spending money.
我不是想冒犯你
Listen, I don't mean to cross the line or anything...
…但是我听说你的爱妻前些年去世了
...but I read about your wife's passing a few years back.
对的  癌症
Yeah, it was woman cancer.
我一直听说她是个很好的人
Yeah. I always heard she was a nice person.
是啊  最好的
Yeah, the best.
- 我认识你？- 我们很早以前见过
- Do I know you?  - We met a long time ago.
我们见过？
We did?
当我还是个孩子时  你送我回家
When I was a kid, you walked me home.
- 是吗？- 劝我戒烟什么的
- I did?  - Told me to stop smoking and things.
戒烟…
Stop smoking...
你就是那个  经常光顾三明治店的小玛丽？
Are you Little Marie that used to hang out at that Atomic Hoagie shop?
对  是的
Yeah, that's right.
现在我想起来了  我送过你回家
Yeah, now I remember. I walked you home.
当你到家后  你转身对我说 "滚你的  马屁精"
When you got there, you turned around and said, "Screw you, creepo."
- 我没那么说过  - 你确实说了
- I didn't say that.  - Yeah, you did.
- 你确定？- 奇耻大辱 怎么会忘记
- You sure?  - Great insults last a long time.
那是你么？真的是你？
Yo! Yo, is that you? Is that really you?
- 你好吗？- 我认为他想要一个人喝酒
- How you doing?  - I think he wants to drink alone.
好  那让他喝去吧  我不拦着你
Well, then give him his drink, then. I ain't stopping you.
怎么了  他是你男人或者… ？不  我不这么认为
What's that, your man or something? No, I don't think so.
总之呢  我和我的朋友刚好在这里
Anyway, me and my friends, we're right down there.
想让你帮我们买单？你那么有钱就帮一次吧
Think you could buy us a round? You got the money. Just one round.
谢谢
Hey. Thank you.
干吗把我手推开？
What are you doing pushing my hand away like that?
- 你叫什么名字？- 安吉 你要知道这干吗？
- What's your name?  - Angie. What do you wanna know for?
- 别为他们做傻瓜  - 傻瓜？
- Don't be playing a fool for that guy.  - A fool?
- 对  - 傻瓜？
- Yeah.  - A fool?
我是个傻瓜？你才是  不是我！
I'm the fool? You're the fool, not me!
你想歪了  你才是傻瓜  我和你一样  都是个人
You got it twisted. You're the fool. I'm a person, just like you.
你比我好不了多少  你当你还是大牌？你屁都不是！
You ain't no better than me. You think you're a big shot now? You're nothing.
你比我好不了多少！好不了多少！
You ain't no better than me. No better!
谢谢你的光顾！
Glad you dropped in?
我觉得邻居有了点小变化
I think the neighborhood is changing a little.
- 刚才出什么事了？- 我不知道 算了吧
- What was that all about?  - I don't know. Forget about it.
我准备关门了  如果你要走的话  这里交给我收拾吧
I'm gonna lock up, so if you wanna take off, I'll tally everything up.
- 好的 谢谢  - 你好吗 洛奇？
- Yeah, thanks.  - How you doing, Rock?
还不错  谢谢
I'm good, thanks.
- 你住在这儿附近？- 离这大概八个街区
- You live around here?  - About eight blocks from here.
八个街区
Eight blocks.
你需要搭个车么？
You need a lift?
好的
All right.
你结过婚吗？
Did you ever get married?
- 是的 算是结过  - 算是？
- Yeah, sort of.  - Sort of?
- 是的 他离开了  - 就这么走了？
- Yeah, well, he took off.  - Poof, just like that?
是的  他就那么走了
Yeah, just like that.
- 你有孩子吗？- 是 我有一个孩子
- You sort of have any kids?  - Yeah, I got one kid.
是么？我也是啊  很棒的男孩
Yeah? Me too. Me too. Wonderful boy.
嘿  混蛋！你怎么回事？请我们喝酒就那么难吗？
Hey, tough guy! What's the matter, you can't buy a round?
这女孩很中意你啊
The girl was being nice to your dumb ass.
- 你和那猪在一起干吗？- 你怎么可以对我们如此无礼？
- What you doing with that pig?  - Think you can disrespect us?
- 她就是个心怀妒忌的婊子  - 你给我过来！
- She ain't nothing but a jealous bitch!  - Come on back!
嘿  别听他们的
Hey, don't listen to them.
你们两个都不比我好多少！
Both of youse, you ain't no better than me.
有种过来  把你的头当球踢
Come over here, you'll get your head kicked in around here.
- 你个被打得头晕眼花的野种  - 你不再是大牌了 瞧瞧你
- You punch-drunk, goofy bastard.  - You ain't no big shot, look at you.
你连载一只猪回家的轿车都没有
You ain't even got a car to take that pig home.
你没事吧？
You all right?
没事
Yeah.
你要干什么？别出去  没关系的
What are you doing? Don't get out. It's all right.
不  小玛丽  怎么没事
No, Little Marie. It ain't all right.
- 哟  - 什么？
- Yo.  - What?
我来告诉你  给我进去
I'll tell you what. Get inside.
- 你过来 就你  - 嘿 放开他！
- You get inside. Yeah, you.  - Hey, leave him alone!
- 啊 大哥！- 看到没？
- Yo, man!  - See it?
- 想尝尝这滋味？- 好吧
- You see that? You see that?  - Yeah. All right.
- 说什么？- 对不起 对不起！
- What do you say?  - I'm sorry. I'm sorry!
干正事去！
Get a job!
那家伙道歉了
That guy sends his apologies.
好的
Okay.
马丁  马丁  哟  马丁！
Martin. Martin. Yo, Martin!
原来你还有钥匙
I see you still got your key.
是啊  我有钥匙  有时间聊聊么？
Yeah, I got a key. You got time to talk?
自从你的人让我走以后  我闲得很
I got a lot of time since your people let me go.
你知道  那和我无关
You know I had nothing to do with that.
是啊
Yeah.
我们一年前搬进去的
Yeah, we moved in about a year ago.
- 是吗？- 我意思是 这只是暂时的
- Yeah?  - Yeah, I mean, it's only temporary.
- 是的 我能看出来  - 我正打算找间公寓
- Yeah, I could see that.  - I'm gonna look for an apartment.
公寓很好
Apartments are nice.
是啊  你知道  一分钱一分货
Yeah. It is what it is, you know.
是啊  一分钱一分货
Yeah, it is what it is.
这地方曾经很美丽  这里有着许多的往事
This place used to be pretty nice. There's a lot of history around here.
- 是啊  - 比如这条街尾
- Yeah.  - Like down the street...
有家叫坎布里亚的搏击俱乐部
...is the Cambria fight Club.
过去大家常叫它喋血乐园
They used to call it the Bucket of Blood.
我曾在那打过不少硬仗  但回忆终究是那么美好
I took some massive beatings there. But it was nice. Good memories.
听说这些建筑都有 100 或 150 年的历史了
And I heard these buildings are like, I don't know, 100, 150 years old.
如果我活到 150 岁肯定要散架了  所以这建筑没事的
If I was 150 years old, I'd be falling apart too. So it's okay, building.
那灯能亮吗？
Does that light work?
- 不 可能是里面什么东西烧了  - 是么？
- No, it's burnt out or something. Yeah.  - Yeah?
谢谢你的便车  关于那些小流氓的事  我很抱歉
Listen, thanks for the ride, and I'm sorry about those guys.
他们中的一些不学无术  游手好闲
Some of those guys just got their brains on backwards and stuff.
- 他那么晚了在外面干吗？- 那是你的孩子？
- What's he doing out so late?  - Is that your kid?
是啊  真不希望他那么晚了还在外面晃荡
Yeah. Wish he wouldn't stay out so late.
- 令人惊讶啊  - 怎么了？
- Amazing.  - Yeah, what's that?
我上一次见到你的时候  你还是个孩子
Last time I seen you, you was a kid...
…而现在连小孩都那么大了
...and now you officially got one of your own.
令人惊讶啊
It's amazing.
你觉得么  他有些像你  他有着蓬松的爱尔兰头发
You know, he sort of resembles you. He's got that big Irish hair.
是另一个孩子
Yeah, it's the other one.
- 是么？- 他父亲是牙买加人
- Yeah?  - His father was from Jamaica.
牙买加？欧洲人
Jamaica? European.
游轮上认识的还是什么？
Was you on a cruise ship or something?
- 不 不 真的  - 他叫什么名字？
- No, not really.  - What's his name?
- 斯泰普斯 史蒂文森的小名  - 感觉不错
- Steps. Short for Stevenson.  - Makes sense.
他是不是很生气的在看我？还是我站的角度有问题？
Does he look mad at me, or is it maybe the angle I'm standing at?
不  他是个好孩子
No. He's a good kid.
- 你要见见他么？- 现在有点晚了
- You wanna meet him?  - It's getting kind of late.
- 我还有很多事要忙  - 是啊 我明白
- I got so many things to do.  - Yeah, yeah, I understand.
再次谢谢你所做的
Thanks again for the ride and everything else.
下次见
I'll see you.
You too.
嘿  斯泰普斯  回家吧  和你的朋友说晚安
Hey, Steps, come on. Let's go. Say good night to your friend.
这么冷的天在外面也不戴顶帽子？
What are you doing out in the cold with no hat on?
- 饭吃了么？- 是的 已经吃过了
- Did you get something to eat?  - Yeah, I already ate.
好吧
All right.
- 都那么晚了 知道么？- 我可以自己照顾好自己
- You're late, you know.  - I can take care of myself.
哟  小玛丽！
Yo, Little Marie!
你不打算介绍你儿子给我认识吗？
Ain't you gonna introduce me to your kid?
- 你好吗 斯泰普斯  - 什么事？
- How you doing, Steps?  - What's up?
听着  我有家漂亮的小餐馆在这附近
Listen, I got this place, this restaurant, nice little eatery not too far from here.
什么垃圾东西？一张餐巾纸
What's all this junk? Got a tissue.
有时我觉得我就像个袋鼠  口袋里什么都有
Sometimes I feel like a kangaroo, all the stuff in my pocket, you know.
找到了  我这有张卡
Here you go. I got a card, there it is.
如果你们有机会  很欢迎…
And if you ever get a chance, it'd be great...
你们母子过来吃顿饭
...if both of youse come down there and eat.
我很欢迎  免费的哦  我把它放这里
It'd be great, free. You know. Anyway, I'll leave it over there... Here.
回头见
See you later.
好了  我们走
Come on, let's go.
你从 10 岁开始就懂得什么是对你最好的？
You've known what' best for you since you were 10.
自从你独自一人来到这里
Since you walked in here alone.
所有钱能买到的都有了…
Got everything money can buy...
但是也有钱买不到的
...except what it can't.
那就是尊严  有尊严才能脱离贫民生活
It's pride. Pride is what got your ass out of here.
失败带你再次回到这里
Losing is what brung you back.
像你这种人需要的是考验  需要的是挑战
But people like you, they need to be tested. Need a challenge.
那不可能  我已经无敌了
That ain't gonna happen. Ain't nothing out there.
人外有人  天外有天  一定会有的
There's always somebody out there. Always.
每一天  某人站在你面前…
When that time comes and you find something...
不逃避  不退缩
...standing in front of you that ain't running...
猛烈地击打着你  你被累到喘不过气来
...that ain't backing up, hitting on you, and you're too damn tired to breathe...
当这个情况发生在你身上时  那是好事
You find that situation on you, that's good.
因为那是 "战火" 的洗礼
Because that's baptism under fire.
你度过了那一关  你会认识到…
You get through that, you find the only kind of respect...
这世界上唯一的一种尊敬
...that matters in this damn world:
自尊
Self-respect.
谢谢你  马丁  我很感激
Thanks, Martin. I appreciate that.
现在  我这个拳王能为你做些什么呢？
Now, what can the champ do for you?
你可以给我些钱啊
You can give me some of that money you got.
- 你知道 我喜欢你 马丁  - 但你更喜欢钱
- You know, I like you, Martin.  - But not that much.
正如你所言
Exactly.
和我孩子合个影好么？
How about a picture with the kid? All right?
当然
Sure.
孩子  抬起你的拳头  这会使你看起来更凶猛一点
Here, son, hold up your fist. Makes you look more hazardous.
- 你们继续  - 谢谢 洛奇
- There you go.  - Thanks, Rock.
用餐愉快
Enjoy your meal.
- 他人不错吧？- 洛奇？
- He's a nice guy, isn't he?  - Rocky?
- 是的  - 斯柏德刚下楼去了
- Yeah.  - Spider just went downstairs.
- 我不知道那样是否要紧  - 他要干什么？
- I don't know if that's all right.  - What's he doing?
我不知道  那是你朋友啊
I don't know. That's your friend.
斯柏德！
Yo, Spider!
- 让我洗些盘子 这样我感觉好些  - 别这样 你是我的客人
- Let me do some dishes. I feel better.  - Come on. You're my guest.
- 让我做点什么吧  - 你是客人 只管吃就行了
- Let me do something.  - Keep eating. Guests do that.
可别惹我再和你搏斗了  上一次只是你运气好
Don't make me fight you again. Last time you got lucky.
运气？好吧
Lucky? Okay.
耶稣需要我去工作
Jesus wants me to work.
- 洛奇  - 是？
- Yo, Rocky.  - Yeah?
你有客人来了
You've got guests.
别弄得太湿  好吧？
Don't get too wet, okay?
还好耶稣没要你下厨
Glad Jesus didn't ask you to cook.
卡你们还留着啊
You kept the card.
是的  我还留着这卡
Yeah, I kept the card.
- 为什么不先坐下呢？- 好 当然
- Why don't you sit down?  - Yeah, sure.
因为  你知道我怎么做的么  我走过去  问个好  然后这样
Because, you know what, I walk in there, I say good morning, I do this:
今晚  又有一场拳击较量
Tonight, boxing once again.
两位风格炯异的拳王
Two contrasting styles in almost every way.
嘿  能调响一点么？请调响一点
Hey, can you turn this up? Turn this up, please.
谁才是一直以来最棒的拳手呢？如果两位不同时代的拳王…
Who was the best of all time? If two athletes from different eras...
…能够同场竞技  谁能登上世界的顶峰呢？
...could compete against one another, who would come out on top?
同样的规则  同样的装备  谁才是最好的呢？
Given the same rules, using the same equipment, who was the greatest?
我们把实际数据输入电脑
We feed our facts into the computer.
他们全盛时期的体重
They weigh in on who they think will reign supreme...
还有我们资深体育版记者的评价
...while fielding the comments of our illustrious panel of sportswriters.
拳王！
Champ!
- 哟 拳王！- 嗯？
- Yo, champ!  - Yeah?
过来看看这些废物  他们在谈论着你  伙计！
Come check out this trash they're talking about you, man!
- 他们说什么了？- 过来看下 快点
- What you talking about?  - Come check this out. Hurry up.
今晚  曾经的两次最重量级拳王
Tonight, the former two-time heavyweight champion...
来自费城的洛奇·巴尔博亚
...from Philadelphia, Rocky Balboa.
查克·约翰逊 《今日美国》
All right, Chuck Johnson, USA Today?
毫无疑问  洛奇·巴尔博亚在拳台上打过很多硬仗
There' no question that Rocky Balboa fought tougher fights...
在那个艰苦的时代
...during a tougher era in boxing.
你们看梅森·迪克逊的职业生涯…
You look at Mason Dixon in his career...
他基本上被他的对手宠坏了
...he' basically been spoon-fed his opponents.
在我看来  毫无疑问  洛奇不仅获胜
No question in my mind. Not only does Rocky win...
而且他将击倒对手
...but he wins knockout.
洛奇！
Rocky!
后代…
Offspring.
伯纳德·费尔南德斯？
Bernard Fernandez?
迪克逊是自己优势的受害者
Dixon is a victim of his own dominance.
他从没经历过真正激烈的持久战
He' never been in real knockdown-dragout brawls.
从没有被放倒后重整旗鼓的经历
He never had to dig down to rally back.
如果他想要放倒巴尔博亚
If he tries to dig down against Balboa...
他会发现他还没有足够大的铲子
...he'll find he doesn't have a big enough shovel.
我很明确支持巴尔博亚
I clearly give it to Balboa.
你怎么了？你怎么了？
What happened to you? What happened to you?
拳击历史学家  波特·兰道夫·苏加
Boxing historian Burt Randolph Sugar.
迪克逊只打过懦夫  我们不清楚他的真正实力
Dixon has fought cream puffs. We don't know what he' made of.
但是在他们的颠峰期  我们必须承认这个事实…
But both in their primes, you gotta factor in...
迪克逊有着不可思议的速度…
...Dixor unbelievable speed...
尖锐的进攻  他会把巴尔博亚切成肉片
...his slashing offense. He cuts Balboa to bits.
毫无疑问  迪克逊会轻松获胜
No doubt. Dixon wins all the way.
我们的主观猜测到此结束  让我们看看计算机的模拟
Here' where our subjectivity ends. Let' see what the computer says.
迪克逊摆脱了巴尔博亚  洛奇没有还手  巴尔博亚连吃刺拳
Dixon unloads on Balboa. Rocky has no answer. Balboa is eating jabs.
- 现在什么时间？- 梅森时间
- What time is it?  - Mason time.
现在迪克逊要完蛋了  他摇摇晃晃的  他脚都快站不稳了！
Now Dixon is done. He is reeling. He is almost out on his feet!
巴尔博亚热情高涨  几乎要把他打出拳台
Balboa turning up the heat. Pounds him across the ring.
我相信他快坚持不住了  看吧
Boy, he' bit off more than he can chew this time. Believe it.
一记致命的右勾拳！迪克逊站不住了
Oh, a murderous right hook! And Dixon is out on his feet.
他活生生的倒在了拳台上
He is out cold as he crumbles to the canvas.
胜利者是巴尔博亚
And it is Balboa who has won...
女士们  先生们  小洛奇  小洛奇
Ladies and gentlemen, Baby Rocky. Baby Rocky.
我很高兴你能喜欢吃这些菜
I'm glad you liked the food.
明早你把它热一热  当早餐很不错
If you heat that up, it's pretty good in the morning.
谢谢  伙计
Yeah, thanks, man.
不错的孩子  希望这音乐不会让你头疼  我就喜欢怀旧金曲
Nice kid. I hope this music ain't giving you a headache. I like this old stuff.
不  我非常喜欢  好听
No, I like it. It's nice.
好  不错
Well, good. Good.
你觉得斯泰普斯需要工作吗？周末赚点零用钱？
Yo, you think Steps wants a job? Make a few bucks on the weekend?
自己动手丰衣足食  我孩子就靠这藏了不少私房钱
It's good making your own G's. My kid stashed a few bucks doing that.
你为什么对我们这么好？
Why are you being so nice?
你可千万不要想歪了
I don't want you to think nothing's off, you know.
是的  我妻子过世了  但是我却仍然想念着她
My wife, she's gone, but she ain't. You know what I mean?
嗯  好的  我没那么想  相信我
Yeah, well, I wasrt thinking that. Believe me.
- 没有？那你在想什么呢？- 没什么
- No? Then what was you thinking?  - No.
因为你不欠我们什么人情  你在干吗？
That you don't owe us nothing. What are you doing?
耐心点
Be patient.
现在…
Now...
我是不欠你什么  但是为什么
...I don't owe you nothing, but why do you gotta...
你一定要欠了恩情才能回报呢？
...owe something to get...?
亮了
Bingo.
为什么非要欠了恩情才能回报呢？真的
Why do you gotta owe something to get something, you know? Really.
我觉得带着你孩子随便逛很开心  你觉得呢？
I think hanging out with your kid would be nice. What do you think?
我觉得是很开心
I think that'd be nice.
好  那非常好
Good. That's very nice.
你能来玩我很高兴
I'm glad you come by.
看着你吃东西  我很开心
It was nice watching you eat.
好伙伴
Good company.
哟  小玛丽  让它亮着吧！
Yo, Little Marie. Let there be light!
- 你喜欢狗么？- 狗？
- You like dogs?  - Dogs?
狗  这像个狗的收容所
Dogs. This is like a dog pound. It's where they keep...
这养着许多各式各样的狗  我过去经常来这里参观
...a large variety of dogs. I used to come here all the time for sightseeing.
但是  你知道么  你会从和狗的交流中学到很多
But, you know, you learn a lot talking to dogs.
- 真的 你可以  - 是 伙计 那么…
- Really, you do.  - Yeah, man. So...
嘿  伙计  这只怎么样？
Hey, man, how about this one?
他看来不是太友善  我的朋友
He don't look too friendly, my friend.
伙计  这是唯一一只  嘿  小狗  你好吗？
Man, this is the one. Hey, boy, how you doing?
这里的这只怎么样？过来看  孩子
Hey, what about this one here? Come here, boy.
- 哪只 就他？- 是 不可以么？
- Who, him?  - Yeah, why not?
天那  不  这只狗真丑  伙计
Hell, no. That is one ugly dog, man.
我知道  但这是种很聪明的狗  如果你仔细观察  这毛色…
I know, but it's kind of a cute ugly. If you look at it closely, the color...
看起来就像旧家具的颜色  又有点像海盗的藏宝箱的颜色
...it looks like old furniture, like some kind of pirate-chest thing going on.
对  当然  伙计  嘿  那么这个年轻的呢？
Yeah, sure, man. Hey, so how about a young one?
斯泰普斯  忘了他  看这个  我要你看明白一些东西
Steps, forget him. Come over here. I want you to see something.
现在  你注意到这个动物在干什么？这个姿势躺着
Now, you notice what this animal is doing here? Lying in that position?
他什么也没干
He ain't doing nothing.
不  他干了许多事  他不想浪费精力
No, he's doing a lot. He ain't wasting no energy.
因为他已经死了
Because he's dead.
他没死  他还有很多路要走
He ain't dead. There's a lot of good mileage left on that animal.
享受美食  交很多新朋友  当然  他会卷土重来
Good food, the addition of a couple of new friends, bingo, he's back.
- 你想到什么好名字么？- 他是你的狗 你给他取吧
- What do you think is a good name?  - It's your dog. You name him.
不  他是我们共有的  对半开
No. It's, like, a community animal. Fifty-fifty.
瞧吧  我对狗并不是很了解
Look, I don't know much about no dogs.
好吧  不需要很复杂的
Well, it ain't that complicated.
你宠他  你养他  顺其自然吧
You pet him, you feed him, and nature takes its course.
你知道  所以… 你不想给这个小动物起名字么？
You know, so... Don't you wanna name an animal?
每个人曾经都尝试过给动物起名字
Every guy should at one time try to name an animal something.
我不知道  叫 "睡袋" 吧？
I don't know. Fleabag?
好记  但没有创新  不过还不错吧
It's catchy. It ain't original, but it's pretty good.
我觉得你还是要开动脑筋
I think you could come up with, in your young brain...
想个比 "睡袋" 更好的名字
...something better to throw out than fleabag.
沙袋  这个怎样？
Punchy. How's that?
- 沙袋？- 好 沙袋
- Punchy?  - Yeah, Punchy.
- 我喜欢 你知道  - 真的？
- I like it, you know.  - For real?
真的  就沙袋了  好记  也不难拼写
Yeah, for real. Punchy it is. It's easy to remember, it's not that hard to spell.
一旦记住  永远不忘  沙袋  非常不错
And once it's in your brain, you never forget it. Punchy. Very good.
- 好吧 伙计  - 不错的称呼
- All right, man.  - Good call.
好吧  沙袋  你准备好获得自由了么  我的朋友？
All right, Punchy. You ready to get bailed out, my friend?
好的
Okay.
嘿  你知道我是在开玩笑？
Hey, you know it was a joke, don't you?
是的  我知道  你是个非常有趣的家伙
Yeah, I know. You're a very funny guy.
洛奇？
Rocky?
"观众们都流露出了不满的情绪"
"The fans let him know how they feel about it."
- 失陪  - 没事
- Excuse me.  - Sure.
"情况就快失控了"
"This could get ugly."
- 洛奇  - 哟 保利
- Rock.  - Yo, Paulie.
他们在谈论那场  打得很假的比赛
They're gonna be talking about that fake Looney Tune fight.
来吧  我们正打算供应今天的特色菜
Hey, come on. We're about to serve today's special.
一群墨西哥人烹饪出的意大利食物  有什么特殊的？
Italian food cooked up by a bunch of Mexicans ain't so special.
嘿
Hey, yo.
嘿  我逃了工作就为看这个
Hey, I skipped work for this.
好丑的一只狗
What an ugly dog.
它是只很聪明的狗
It's a cute dog.
- 洛奇  - 什么？
- Hey, Rock.  - Yeah?
我准备走了  后面的那些奖状照片真是太酷了
I'm gonna take off. That stuff back there is pretty cool.
- 你喜欢么？- 当然 朋友
- Oh, you like that?  - Yeah, man.
- 谢谢 我很高兴  - 下次见了
- Thanks, I appreciate it.  - I'll catch you later.
好的
All right.
- 这个长的像罪犯是谁？- 他是个好孩子
- Who's the criminal?  - He's a nice kid.
他穿得像个小流氓
He dresses like a bum.
从一个碍事的人口中说出  那已经可以算是一个恭维了
Coming from a human hamper, that's quite a compliment.
把银餐具收起来了
Hide the silverware.
那很好
That's nice.
嘿  斯柏德
Hey, Spider.
你不是击倒过他一次么？
Didrt you knock out that bum once?
你一边歇着不行么？
Will you give it a rest?
我为了看这个都快迟到了  你就让我看看好吗？
I'm gonna be late for work for this. Give me a break, huh?
好吧  只看一会儿
All right. Just for a few seconds.
60 年代后期  在默罕默德·阿里和
In the late '60s, a simulated fight took place between two legends...
洛奇·马克西亚诺这两位传奇人物之间
...Muhammad Ali and Rocky Marciano.
举行过一场模拟比赛  现在马克西亚诺早已退休
Marciano long retired, and Ali unable to fight legitimately...
而因拒服兵役的罪名被罚禁赛三年的阿里
...for three years for having refused induction into the armed forces...
由于经济拮据  接受了这场梦幻般的比赛
...was in need of money, and agreed to the dream match...
比赛的结果由电脑来模拟决定
...whose outcome would be decided by a computer.
距离洛奇·马克西亚诺赢得上场
It' almost 35 years since Rocky Marciano...
颇具争议的电脑模拟比赛已将近 35 年了
...won the much-disputed computer decision...
你猜怎么着？完全没有改变
...and guess what? Not much has changed.
上周洛奇·巴尔博亚获得了一场决定性的胜利
Last week, Rocky Balboa won a decisive fight...
看到了么？这个就是我给你说的卡通格斗
See? That's the can'toon fight I'm telling you about.
是啊
Yeah.
一次令人印象深刻的击倒获胜
A stunning knockout.
请大家记住  这场比赛没有人为因素干预
Keep in mind, this is taking the human factor out of it.
- 电脑认为巴尔博亚…  - 打得漂亮
- The computer says Balboa...  - Beautiful.
…将在第 13 回合击倒对手获胜  争议随之而来
...would be triumphant, KO 13. And here' some of the fallout:
原本形式简单的娱乐节目
What started as a simple form of entertainment...
现在却变成了叫阵 观众们
...has become a rallying cry for people who think...
认为象巴尔博亚这种老选手  可以表现得再好一点
...an old-school athlete like Balboa could actually be better.
而用电脑科技创造的虚拟世界  就显得不切实际
Computer technology has to create what isn't. That' just not responsible.
去找精神科医生吧
Get therapy, will you?
你认为巴尔博亚和迪克逊打胜算如何？
How do you think Balboa would have done against Dixon?
会很惨  我个人不太同意  巴尔博亚完全被高估了
Badly. Personally, I think Balboa was completely overrated.
他在费城南部有家餐馆
He owns a restaurant in South Philly.
有什么特别的  是拳打鸡吗？
What' the specialty, pounded chicken?
不管怎样  如果真比  我还是愿意出钱去看这比赛的
Anyway, I would have paid to see the fight. Next topic, NAS CAR...
下个话题  纳斯卡比赛  这场争论还将继续…
...and the controversy that won't go away.
让我们回到周日的比赛…
Let' go back to Sunday' race...
嘿  嘿  嘿  振作起来
Hey, hey, hey, cheer up.
为你免费做广告啊  走了  我该去上班了
It's free advertisement. Come on. Meat house calls.
哟  罗伯特
Yo, Robert.
你那么晚了还在外面干吗？
What are you doing out so late?
我打过电话  但是没人接
I tried calling, but nothing was picking up.
- 有什么事吗？- 我只是想过来…
- Is something wrong?  - I just wanted to come by...
- …看看你  - 想进来坐一会吗？
- ...and see you in person.  - Wanna come inside?
不了  我只是想问下你对一些事的看法
No. I just wanna get your opinion on something.
好的  什么方面的看法？
Sure. Opinion on what?
你听说过 "人生不能重来" 吗  对吧？
You know, they say you only go around once, right?
- 对 我听过  - 好的…
- Yeah, I've heard that.  - Well...
…我觉得我该做点什么  比如…
...I think I wanna, like, do something.
- 比如什么？- 拳击
- Like what?  - Fight.
你知道  没必要大型的  小规模的  比如地区比赛
You know, nothing big. Small stuff, like locally. You know.
你不认为你太… 老了么？
Don't you think you're too, you know, old?
你觉得你应该停止尝试…
You think you ought to stop trying things...
…仅仅是因为  你过了很多生日么？我不会
...because you had a few too many birthdays? I do not.
别人会认为你疯了的
People will think you're crazy.
有什么比和对手对峙  然后说 "正是我" 更疯狂呢？
What's crazy about standing toe to toe saying, "I am," you know?
那样说太自大了
That's just ego talking.
你要向别人证明什么呢？
What are you trying to prove to other people, Pop?
证明什么？听着  我不管…
Prove? Listen, I stopped thinking...
…别人过去是怎么想的
...the way other people think a long time ago.
做好你自己就行了
You gotta think like you think.
- 我是这样想的  - 是么？很好
- I do.  - Do you? Good.
你面对现实  好么？今时不同往日
You gotta face reality, okay? It's a different world now.
仅仅是衣服不同而已
Only the clothes is different.
我真不知道  你要从我这得到什么看法
I really don't know what you want from me.
我只是喜欢我们能更团结  你知道  就像一支主队
I just wanted us to get involved. You know, like, home team.
听着  无论你过去经历过什么  那终究是过去
Look, whatever it is, whatever you're going through, it'll pass.
是啊  或许你是对的
Yeah, you're probably right.
我们逃不过岁月的蹉跎
Time is gonna catch up to all of us.
- 尤其当你停滞不前的时候  - 嘿 来吧
- Especially if you're standing still.  - Hey, come on.
我明天上午再给你打电话
Look, I'm gonna call you in the morning.
- 你把这个想法告诉你儿子了？- 是的 说了
- Did you tell this to your kid?  - Yeah, I did.
- 他怎么想的？认为你胡扯 是么？- 差不多
- What'd he think, you're nuts, right?  - Yeah.
看吧  他不相信你？欢迎来我的世界  伙伴
Oh, well, he don't believe in you? Welcome to my world, buddy.
洛奇  没有人会给你拳王头衔
Rocko, nobody's giving you no title shot.
我知道  我也不需要
I know that. I don't want one.
那么是不是精神上受了什么打击？
So this isn't a mental disturbance?
不
No.
你疯了因为他们诋毁了你的形象？
You're mad because they took down your statue?
不
No.
真的不是
Not really, no.
如果是因为钱的原因  那么你只要在胸前挂块牌子
If it's about money, just hang a sign around your neck saying, "Punch me."
"五美圆打一拳"  那么你就可以发财了
Five dollars, you'll make big money.
怎么？你还没有登上过拳坛顶峰？
What? You haven't peaked yet?
- 顶峰？- 是的 顶峰
- Peaked?  - Yeah, peaked.
我不知道  总觉得有些事积压在心里
I don't know. There's still some stuff in the basement.
- 哪里？- 这里 心底
- What basement?  - In here.
告诉我吧
Tell me about the stuff.
- 关于什么？- 说说你心底的事吧
- What about it?  - Tell me about the stuff inside.
- 是愤怒么？- 愤怒？
- Is it angry?  - Angry?
你是不是  因为艾黛丽安的离开而发疯了？
Are you mad because Adrian left you?
她没有离开我  保利  她去世了
She didn't leave, Paulie. She died.
好  好  好  好
Okay. Okay, okay, okay.
你知道么  有时我觉得呼吸都困难
You know, sometimes it's hard to breathe.
你知道么  我感觉就像有野兽在我身体里
You know, I feel, like, this beast inside me.
会没事的  洛奇  会没事的
It's okay, Rocko. Please, it's okay.
会没事么？
Is it okay?
我甚至从来不知道它会如此的猛烈
I just never knew it was supposed to be this hard.
本不应该这样的  保利  你明白的…
It wasrt supposed to be like this, Paulie. You know, it...
那么你能过来  协助我训练么？
So you wanna come by and help me train?
我这里有工作
I got a job here.
我明白
I understand.
记得你说过 "如果你在一个地方呆久了…
Remember you said if you stay one place long enough...
…你就会对那地方有感情了"
...you become that place?
洛奇  这就是我现在的全部
Rocko, this is all I got.
我知道  保利  确实
I understand, Paulie. I do.
如果你有时间  过来看我训练  我会很高兴的
If you get time and come down and see me train, I'd appreciate it.
当然  洛奇
Of course, Rocko.
再见  保利
Bye, Paulie.
再见  洛奇
Goodbye, Rocko.
保重  洛奇
Take care, Rocko.
这次宾夕法尼亚州  体育委员会全体会议…
This plenary session of the Pennsylvania Athletic Commission...
…召开是为了  考虑洛奇·巴尔博亚的申请…
...is convened in order to consider the application of Rocky Balboa...
关于是否颁发给他  自由职业拳击执照
...for the issuance of a discretionary professional boxing license...
由于获得许可是一项权利
...due to his ineligibility to be licensed as a matter of right.
巴尔博亚先生  欢迎你来这里  因为你自己代表的是自己…
Mr. Balboa, you're welcome here. Since you're representing yourself...
如果你愿意的话  我们邀请你作一个开幕陈辞
...we invite you to make an opening statement, if you'd like to.
不  我只对我自己怎么打有兴趣  就是这样
No, I was just curious how I did, that's all.
好吧  这样  医疗顾问团通知我们
All right, well, the Medical Advisory Board has informed us...
你做的那些成套的测验
...that the battery of tests to which you've been subjected...
你已经全部出色的通过了
...you've passed these tests with flying colors.
我们为此祝贺你
And we congratulate you for that.
- 谢谢  - 然而 本委员会…
- Thanks.  - However, this commission...
出于良心的考虑  不能推荐给你这个执照
...in good conscience, cannot recommend you for a license...
因此我们拒绝你的申请
...and we therefore deny your application.
- 我是不是按照你们的申请程序做的？- 是的
- Didrt I do what you asked?  - Yes, you did.
那么我就可以得到拳击执照  是么？
So I should get a license, right?
不完全是
Not exactly.
如果你们不想让我通过  为什么你们还让我做所有的测试？
So why did you give me all them tests if you was never passing me?
我们有我们的立场
We've gotta stand by our decision here...
这次我们不得不拒绝你的申请
...and we have to deny your request for a license at this time.
难道我就没有什么权利么？
Yo, don't I got some rights?
你所说的是什么权利？
What rights do you think you're referring to?
比如写在大街小巷那些官方文件
Like in that official paper they wrote down the street?
- 那是权利与自由法案  - 权利和自由法案
- That's the Bill of Rights.  - Bill of Rights.
它上面不是说了  关于做你觉得快乐的事情？
Don't it say something about going after what makes you happy?
不  那是"对幸福的追求"  你要说什么？
No, that's "the pursuit of happiness." But what's your point?
我要说的是我正在追求的  有人看来为此感到不太高兴
My point is I'm pursuing something, and nobody looks too happy about it.
但是我们正是从你的利益角度考虑的
But we're just looking out for your interests.
我很感谢  但是可能你照顾你自己的利益更多些
I appreciate that, but maybe you're looking out for your interests more.
你不应该叫人来这里  还浪费车钱
You shouldn't ask people to come here and pay the freight on something.
即使他们花了钱  还是没什么好结果  你觉得那样对么？
They pay, it still ain't good enough. You think that's right?
或许这是你们在尽责  但为什么一定要阻止我尽责？
Maybe you're doing your job, but why you gotta stop me from doing mine?
如果你愿意经历所有的苦难  来得到你想要得到的
If you're willing to go through all the battling to get where you want to get...
谁有权利来阻止你呢？
...who's got the right to stop you?
或许你有什么未完成的心愿  或许你有什么未能达成的事
Maybe you got something you never finished, something you wanna do.
或许有什么未对某人说的话  或许！
Something you never said to somebody, something!
然后你被告知"不行"  即使在你付出了应有的权利后
And you're told no, even after you pay your dues.
谁有这个权利对你说不？谁？没有人可以！
Who's got the right to tell you that? Who? Nobody!
有权利去倾听自己的内心  在你获得做你自己的权利…
It's your right to listen to your gut. It's nobody's right to say no...
做你想做的事情之后  没有人有权利对你说不！
...after you earn the right to be what you wanna be or do what you wanna do!
人越老  该抛弃的东西越多  那才是生活
The older I get, the more things I gotta leave behind. That's life.
我对你们唯一的请求就在那桌子上  那才是权利
The only thing I'm asking you guys to leave on the table is what's right.
哟！看今天的报纸了么？
Yo! Have you seen the paper today?
头条新闻！头条新闻！
Front row. Front row.
那真是太棒了
That is so great.
- 好吧 好吧  - 我们去吃点东西
- All right, all right.  - Let's go get some food. Food.
- 喝杯酒去 走啦  - 来啊
- Let's get a beer. Come on.  - Come on.
近两期付费平台的拳赛几乎无人问津
The last two pay-per-views were in the toilet.
重量级拳王锦标赛赚不到钱了
You're not making heavyweight-championship money.
外面都是些无名小卒  梅森
There's a bunch of nobodies out there, Mase.
我想和你谈谈  关于一个赚钱的好机会
I wanna talk to you about an opportunity we should run with.
看着我
Look at me.
有没有听说洛奇·巴尔博亚已经申请到拳击执照呢？
You heard Rocky Balboa applied for a license and got one?
- 我知道 不值一提  - 听我说完
- I heard. Forget about him.  - Hear me out.
你要我和这个双手背着都能打赢的家伙比赛么？
You want me to fight a guy I can beat with both hands tied behind my back.
大家都知道你坐着也能打赢  但这不是比赛的重点
Everybody knows you could beat him sitting down. That's not what it's about.
重点是赚钱  我们要投资电脑拳击赛
It's about making money. We gotta capitalize on that computer fight.
这场比赛可以卖出百万张票  你能赚到一、两千万呢
This could do a million buys. That's 15, 20 million to you.
- 算了吧  - 现在已经没有人敲门…
- Forget it.  - No one's beating the door down...
- …来看你比赛了  - 不让我们办一场包赢的比赛
- ...to watch you fight anymore.  - We got guaranteed fights.
如果你现在做的话  你就会马上在你朋友面前泄漏秘密
You wanna do this now in front of your friends, we'll do it now.
那我们就一无所有了  所有的付费频道都拒绝了你
We got nothing. All the pay-per-view fights you come up with got rejected.
知道为什么吗？你的对手太弱  比赛不够刺激
You know why? They're all bums out there. Nobody cares about them.
已经没有看点了  但是这个巴尔博亚很有趣
There's no marquee value. But this Balboa thing is interesting.
- 我不想和他打  - 听我说
- I don't wanna do it.  - Listen to me.
他曾经盛极一时  但是现在时代不同了
It's a has-been, never-gonna-be world.
不管是怀旧还是其他的原因都行
And you call it nostalgia, whatever you want...
只要能引起观众的共鸣  这是比只赚不亏的买卖
...but people relate to that stuff. This is a no-lose everybody.
- 而且有好处- 对谁有好处？
- It's all good.  - Good for who?
对你！对我！对你！
For you! Not for me! For you!
也许你还不明白  人们已经不再喜欢你了
Maybe you don't understand. People don't like you no more.
他们不再追随你  不再支持你  明白么？
They  don't  follow  you.  They're  not  supporting  you  anymore.  Understand?
别那样看着我  好像我在搞砸你的比赛信条
Don't  look  at  me  like  I'm  messing  with  your  legacy.
每个运动员都认为他们拥有一个信条
Every jock now thinks they got a legacy.
信条是你付钱也买不到的  那才是一个信条
A legacy is what you get instead of getting paid. That's a legacy.
- 别当我傻瓜  - 我没有
- Don't talk to me like I'm stupid.  - I'm not no more.
每个人都知道你可以把这个老东西打翻  但是你不能
Everybody knows you could kick this old mars ass. But you don't.
留给他一些自尊  然后别人就会说
Leave him with a little dignity, so they say:
"梅森·迪克逊有同情心  他是个好人  是个正派的人"
"Mason Dixors got compassion. He's a decent guy, he's a nice guy."
你得个满堂彩  以后出场费就可以翻倍了
You get a whole new audience, we'll double your money.
你想换个新形象吗？这就是机会
You want a new image? That's how you get it.
换掉你们两个设计的形象？
To replace the one that you two made?
等等  我们让你铺平道路  你做剩下的事就行
Whoa, wait. We made your world green. You made the rest.
这才是你  你让所有这些蠢事发生
This is you. You made all this junk happen.
我已经把这里变得一团糟了
I've had it up to here with this mess.
是时候让我做些改变了  我要去马丁的体育馆了
Time for me to make changes. I'm going to Martirs gym.
- 我们再谈谈这个事  - 忘了这个蠢事吧
- We'll talk about it.  - Forget this crap.
我要马丁回来  不然什么都免谈
I want Martin back. There's nothing to talk about.
- 你好吗？- 嘿 真让我吃惊
- How you doing?  - Hey, what a surprise.
我正好在这附近逛逛  我想…
I was driving around the neighborhood, I thought...
…为什么不过来打个招呼呢？- 进来坐一会吗？
...why not drive by and say hello?  - You wanna come inside?
不  我要溜溜狗  你想出来散散步么？
No, the dog needs some exercise. You wanna take a little walk?
- 好 好 当然  - 外面天气很好
- Yeah, yeah. All right.  - It's nice outside.
- 是的  - 天气很好很冷
- All right.  - Nice and brisk.
什么时候买的狗？
When did you get a dog?
我们几天前领养的 "沙袋"
We picked up Punchy a couple of days back.
- "沙袋"？- 是啊
- Punchy?  - Yeah.
你给你的狗取名叫 "沙袋"？
You named your dog Punchy?
你孩子想出来的名字
Your kid come up with the name.
哦  是吗？我觉得那样太没礼貌了
Oh, yeah? I think that's disrespectful.
不  不  没事  真的
Oh, no, no. It's fine, really.
很不错  很好记  你不觉得？
No, it's easy to remember and it's all that, you know.
听着  想过来餐馆吗？
Listen, what do you think about coming over to the restaurant?
- 来干吗？- 你知道 比如过来…
- What for?  - Well, you know, for, like...
来工作  女领班快要生孩子了  你来顶替她不错
for work. The hostess is gonna be having a kid. You'd do good.
- 我不知道  - 我告诉你 你能做得很好
- I don't know.  - I'm telling you, you'd do so good.
我很感激你为我孩子所做的  但是我不能
I appreciate what you're doing for my kid, but I can't.
嘿  听着  我认为你会很喜欢的
Hey, listen, I think you'd like it a lot.
不错的环境  非常舒服
It's a nice environment, it's very pleasant.
是啊  我们能不能不谈这个？
Yeah, can we drop it?
你有什么担心的？
What's bothering you?
没什么  很好  听着  我要回去了
Nothing. It's all right. Listen, I gotta get back.
- 不 不好  - 哦 得了
- No, it ain't all right.  - Oh, come on.
- 什么？- 我会成为…
- What?  - I'm gonna be the first person...
…顾客走进店里第一个看到的人？- 你只是分发菜单
...people see when they walk in?  - You give out menus.
向顾客问好  安排他们就座
You say, "Hello, how are you?" You sit people down.
听着  我能做的事  任何其他人都能做的
Look, if I can do it, anybody can do it.
你可以找到 10 个甚至 100 个更胜任这工作的人
You could find 10 better people, a hundred better people for this job.
试一试  哪怕就两个礼拜
Give it a try, like two weeks.
我不想试
I don't wanna try.
- 你脑子里想什么呢？- 没什么
- Who put this stuff in your head?  - Nobody.
那这想法也不可能  自己钻进你脑袋的
Well, it just don't get in there by itself.
谢谢你过来
Thanks for coming by.
你最近一次去跳舞是什么时候？是不是很久了？
Yo, when was the last time you went dancing? Has it been a while?
- 为什么问这个？- 因为…
- Why are you asking?  - I'm asking because...
你总是跟这些烦恼"跳舞"  你也许也愿意跟我跳舞
...you dance around these problems, you might as well dance with me.
我不是跳得很好  但是比一般水平还是要好
I ain't that good, but I'm better than the average bear.
这是怎么想出来的  我自己也不知道
Where that came from, I don't know.
- 你疯了  - 有点
- You're crazy.  - A little bit.
但是你思考和说话的方式  同样也有点疯
But the way you're thinking and talking, it's a little crazy too.
快点  你应该拥有更好的  真的  过来帮忙吧
Come on, you deserve better. Really. Come on over.
我需要你打理我的地方  整个费城也需要你
I need you to class my place up. Philly needs you.
如果你还会说 "滚你的  马屁精"  我也完全能理解
And if you say, "Screw you, creepo" again, I totally understand.
但是我警告你  我会让我自己站在马路中间
But I'm warning you, I'm gonna put myself in the middle of the street here...
我和"沙袋"  向过来的第一辆公车摇手
...and stand here, me and Punchy, and wave to the first bus, say:
"过来压碎我吧"！
"Come on over here and mash me!
"小玛丽拒绝了餐馆的工作"
Little Marie turned down the job at the restaurant.
"她认为她比我们优越"
She thinks she's better than us."
哦  是吗？这里已经有 20 年没通过公车了
Oh, yeah? Well, there hasn't been a bus down here in 20 years.
- 是吗？- 对的
- Yeah?  - No.
刚才还真是悬啊
That was a close call.
听着  真的  去我那儿做吧  很不错的
Listen, seriously. Come on over. It'd be nice.
好吧
All right.
保利！
Paulie!
不好意思  保利
Sorry, Paulie.
不好意思
Sorry.
你好吗？把我这个不寻常的东西放那里
How are you? Get my unusual up there.
不好意思  送货的在后面
Excuse me. Deliveries are in the back.
我不是送货的
I'm not a delivery guy.
那你有预定吗？
Well, do you have a reservation?
难道我看上去象印第安人吗？
Do I look like a freaking Indian?
嘿  洛奇  洛奇
Hey, Rock? Rocky?
我认为这家伙有点麻烦
I think we've got a little bit of a problem with this guy.
麻烦？不  不  他是我一个亲戚
Problem? No, no, he's just a relative.
哦  好的
Oh, okay.
保利
Yo, Paulie.
- 你的眼睛怎么了？- 我自己打的
- What happened to your eye?  - I hit it.
- 为什么？- 因为有必要
- Why?  - Needed to.
发生什么事了？
What happened?
- 我在庆祝 洛奇  - 庆祝什么？
- I'm celebrating, Rock.  - Why?
- 我退休了  - 退休？
- I retired.  - Retired?
他们什么时候开始给退休的人发肉…
So when did they start giving retired people meat...
…而不是发手表了  保利？
...instead of watches, Paulie?
我不需要手表
I don't need a watch.
我有手表  你给过我手表！
I got a watch! You gave me a watch!
保利
Paulie...
我才不需要他妈的手表呢
I don't need no goddamn watch.
- 保利  - 我自己有手表！
- Yo, Paulie.  - I got a watch!
我有两块手表！
I got two watches!
保利！
Yo, Paulie!
保利
Yo, Paulie.
洛奇
Rock.
重新回去参赛是需要勇气的  知道你会参赛的
It takes guts climbing back in that ring, knowing you're gonna take a beating.
你做的没错  洛奇
You're gonna do all right, Rocko.
你怎么知道？
How do you know that?
心底里的那些闷事
The stuff in the basement.
谢谢  保利
Thanks, Paulie.
- 嘿  - 嘿 洛奇 你好吗？
- Hey.  - Hey, Rock, how are you?
- 你还好吗？- 是的 很好 你怎么样？
- You okay?  - Yeah, good. How are you?
- 很好 好极了  - 好的
- Yeah, fine. This is great.  - Good.
对了  那边的那些人想跟你谈谈
Listen, some guys over there wanna talk to you.
- 好的 我过去  - 好
- Okay. You got it.  - Okay?
- 多谢惠顾 非常地感谢  - 很荣幸
- Thanks for coming by. I appreciate it.  - Our pleasure.
- 想听故事吗？- 什么故事？
- Wanna hear stories?  - What kind of stories?
很多人都喜欢听那些老的拳赛故事
Well, a lot of people like to hear these old fight stories.
- 也许等会儿吧  - 好的
- Maybe later.  - Okay.
我是鲁·迪贝拉  他是 L. C. 卢克  梅森·迪克逊的经纪人
I'm Lou DiBella. This is L.C. Luco. He's Mason Dixors manager.
- 你能坐下和我们谈谈吗？- 当然
- Will you sit down and join us?  - Sure.
你知道  我们和梅森·迪克逊有宣传合约
You know, we have the promotional contract for Mason Dixon...
- 对了 你还是他的偶像  - 真的？
- ...who's a big fan.  - Really?
当他听说你对拳击又有兴趣时
When he heard you were interested in fighting...
他就想出了一个好点子
...he thought why not try to work something out?
一场特殊的盛会  一场顶级的表演赛
Like a special event. Like a first-class exhibition fight.
- 为什么找我？- 他非常尊敬你
- Why me?  - He respects the hell out of you.
知道吗？我们很有诚意  电脑拳赛引起观众的好奇
All right? And let's be honest, that computer fight got people curious.
- 这可能会很有趣  - 我没有兴趣…
- This could be very interesting.  - I ain't interested...
被人家糟蹋和自取其辱
...in getting, like, mangled and embarrassed.
不  这个情况不会发生  绝对不会
No, that's not gonna happen. Never happen.
坦白说  我更想要的一个…
Truthfully, I was thinking more on a, like...
…小规模的拳击赛  不要盛大比赛  小规模的
...miniscule, small level. You know. Small fights, not big fights.
地方性的  小一点的就行  L. C 你明白我的意思吗？
Small fights. Things that... Local. You know what I mean?
构想不错  不要把它想成是大赛  就把它当成表演赛好了
Not a bad idea. Don't think of it as big. Think of it like an exhibition.
美其名曰是一场拳击示范赛  但细节你会喜欢
Think of it as a glorified sparring session. Here's something you'll like.
我们会捐出部分收入给慈善机构
We're gonna donate a portion of the gate to charity.
- 这是件好事  - 乐善好施
- That's always nice.  - It's good to give.
是啊
Yeah.
在哪里比？
Where's it taking place?
- 拉斯维加斯  - 拉斯维加斯
- Las Vegas.  - Las Vegas.
温暖舒适  这儿都快冻死人了
Nice and warm. This cold's gotta be killing you.
- 快冻僵了  - 暖和一点 步伐会更好
- Little stiff.  - You move better when you're warmer.
- 是啊  - 如果没有其他问题的话…
- Yeah.  - And if nothing else...
…你马上可以有新的故事讲了
...you'll have new stories to tell.
- 你让我好好想想  - 当然
- I really gotta think about this.  - Absolutely.
- 可以吗？- 我理解 没问题
- Is that okay?  - I understand. No problem.
我要去那边了  你们可以点些东西吃
I'm gonna go over there. You can order something.
- 你推荐什么好吃的？- 都是好东西
- What do you recommend?  - It's all edible.
好的  谢谢
Okay. Thanks.
他心动了  如果迪克逊遇上这个老头鼎盛时期
We got him. Imagine if Dixon met this bastard in his prime?
- 他会杀了他的  - 你说的没错
- He'd kill him. Kill him.  - You ain't kidding.
我困惑了
Man, I'm confused.
我从没想过这会真的发生
I didn't think this was gonna come along.
但这就是你想要的  对吗？
But this is what you wanted, right?
我不清楚  你知道  我只是一直说一直说
I don't know. You know, I talk and I talk.
有时候我觉得我说的都是真的
Sometimes I think what I'm saying is true...
然后我看看自己  连自己都不知道什么才是真的
...and then I look at myself and I'm not even sure what is true anymore.
就因为这样  我才有了再比赛的疯狂想法
Because it's like, I pushed this crazy idea about fighting.
我意思是  这都是为什么呢？
I mean, what's it all about?
难道我真的在乎面对面的比赛  或是其他什么…
Do I really care about standing toe to toe and all that stuff...
…也许就像我儿子说的  只是自尊心
...or, like my kid says, is it just, like, ego?
还是我这把老骨头想用  新的伤去替换老伤？
Or am I this old pug who's just trying to replace old pain with new pain?
我不知道  我不知道
I don't know. I don't know.
听着  我懂  我通常不怎么说话
Look, I know I usually don't say a lot.
我总是更愿意倾听和观察
I'm always listening and looking.
但是你这个人  充满生命的个体
But who you are, the part of you that's so full of life...
我们都有这种感觉  这种激情
...we all have that feeling, that fire...
但不是都有机会来释放的  然后激情就会慢慢消失
...but usually never get a chance to use it. And then it just goes away.
但你可以  你有机会  去吧  为什么不呢？
But you can. You've got this opportunity, so do it. Why not?
我意思是  这才是你  这才是真正的你
I mean, this is who you are. This is who you'll always be.
你从不听任何人使唤  总是坚持自己的路
And you don't move aside for nobody until you're ready to move.
别人怎么看没关系
And it doesn't matter how this looks to other people.
重要的是你怎么看
All that matters is how it looks to you.
洛奇
Rocky.
洛奇  看着我
Rocky, look at me.
重要的是你怎么看
How it looks to you.
如果这是你想做的事
And if this is something that you wanna do...
如果这是你非做不可的事  那么就去做吧
...and if this is something that you gotta do, then you do it.
背水一战
Fighters fight.
你不会对我出拳吧？
You're not gonna punch me, are you?
在你开始讨厌我前我必须要走了  明天见
Listen, I gotta go before I wear out my welcome. I'll see you tomorrow.
谢谢
Thanks.
拳手永远战斗  对吗？
Fighters fight, right?
很少有比推广拳击赛更大的活动了  这次就是
It's rare when you get to promote an event bigger than boxing. This is.
技巧对抗意念部分  收益捐给慈善机构
Skill versus will, with part of the proceeds going to charity.
这是梅森·迪克逊的创意  以此向昔日重量级拳王致敬
The brainchild of Mason Dixon, to honor past heavyweight champions.
这位就是洛奇·巴尔博亚  大家可以开始提问
Warriors like Rocky Balboa. Let's open it up for questions.
嘿  洛奇！
Hey, champ!
很少有拳手年逾五十还能打赢拳赛  通常都会惨败
A few great fighters have fought in their 50s, often with disastrous results.
为什么还要冒这个风险  弄得自己难堪？
Why risk the danger and embarrassment?
圈内人士说  你根本没有机会
The smart money says you have virtually no chance.
任何拳手都有机会  这场比赛一定会有看头
A puncher always has a chance. This fight will be competitive.
你为什么要这么做  洛奇？
Why are you doing this, Rocky?
不知道  我宁可做自己热爱的事…
I don't know, I'd rather do something I love badly than...
也不想因为不做而抱憾终生
Than to feel bad by not doing something you love.
洛奇  媒体把你称作已经发酵的巴尔博亚
Rocky, the press has labeled you a Balboasaurus.
你对此什么感觉？
How do you feel about that?
我们这么说吧  你赢了  我们说你只是赢了一个老家伙
Let's say the following happens: You win, we'll say you beat an old guy.
如果你输了  你会成为这十年的笑柄
You lose, say a thumb in the eye, you'll be the joke of the decade.
你们都知道这不可能发生  这只是场表演赛
You all know that will never happen. This is only an exhibition.
不要以为这比电脑拳赛特别很多
Don't go trying to make more out of this than that computer tried.
难道竞技体育还不够麻烦吗？还要搞这种马戏比赛？
Isn't this sport in enough trouble without these circus events?
- 下一个问题  - 表面上
- Next question.  - On the surface, this looks like...
这场比赛就像一场廉价的闹剧  无意冒犯…
...a cheap bit of ring theater between, no offense...
一方是昔日的传奇拳王
...a has-been and a man whose own credible legacy...
另一方的传统和声誉正受到怀疑
...and popularity is in doubt.
- 有什么好处呢？- 怀疑？
- What's the upside?  - Doubt?
好处？我意思是…
Upside? I mean...
你指的好处是什么意思？我该怎么做？
What do you mean, upside? I mean, what do I have to do?
我 33 胜 0 负  其中 30 次击倒对手获胜
You know, I'm 33-0 with 30 knockouts.
我是在帮你们的忙  我是为了你们而参加这场表演赛
I'm doing you people a favor. I'm having this exhibition for you.
你们却站在这里嘲笑我？我是拳王
You gonna get up here and make a mockery out of me? I'm the champ.
我意思是  我火了  这家伙就要挨打
I mean, I get pissed, this guy get hurt.
比赛见
See you at the fight.
这家伙真是个笑柄  肯定被暴打
The guy's a joke. He's gonna get crushed.
- 看谁在这里  - 你好吗？
- Look who's here.  - How you doing?
- 你看到我父亲了吗？- 他在后面
- Have you seen my father?  - He's in the back.
这地方生意从来没这么好过  难以置信
This place has never served this many meals. It's unbelievable.
吃的好吗？希望用餐愉快
You're doing good? Hope you're enjoying everything, all right?
失陪
Excuse me.
你怎么来了？很高兴看到你
How you doing? Glad you come by.
我能跟你谈谈吗？
Can I talk with you?
- 当然  - 能外面谈吗？
- Sure.  - Can we do it outside?
- 你打算进行下去？- 我明天开始训练
- So you're going through with this?  - I start training tomorrow.
嘿  洛奇  我联系了几个人
Hey, Rock. I made some connections.
我可以靠赞助商赚几个小钱
I can make some money on this, endorsements.
当然  去做吧
Absolutely. Do that.
- 谢谢 洛奇 好的  - 没事
- Thank you, Rock. Okay.  - Sure.
- 你对比赛紧张吗？- 怕得要命
- So you nervous about the fight?  - Scared to death.
- 你看上去一点不怕  - 是啊 我没什么好怕的
- You don't look scared.  - Well, I ain't supposed to.
其实你没必要去比赛的
Then you don't have to do it.
是啊  但我认为我应该去
Yeah, well, I think I do.
你知道  和你生活向来不容易
You know, living with you, it hasn't been easy.
人们看着我  想到的却是你
People see me but they think of you.
现在发生的这些事  将会使得这一切更糟
Now with all this going on, it's gonna be worse than ever.
- 不一定会是这样  - 肯定会的！
- It don't have to be.  - Sure it does!
- 怎么了？你一直做得很好 孩子  - 什么 就因为我的姓？
- Why? You've got a lot going on, kid.  - What, my last name?
我才能得到一份体面的工作
That's the reason I got a decent job.
这也是为什么别人总会优先考虑我的原因
That's why people deal with me in the first place.
现在我开始有点成绩了
Now I start to get a little ahead...
开始能做出点自己的小成绩了  却又发生了这事
...I start to get a little something for myself, and this happens.
现在  我请求你帮我个忙  不要再进行下去了
Now, I'm asking you as a favor not to go through with this.
这事情的结局不会对你有好处  也同样不会对我有好处
This is gonna end up bad for you, and it's gonna end up bad for me.
- 你认为我是在伤害你？- 是的 某种意义上 你是在伤害我
- You think I'm hurting you?  - Yeah. In a way, you are.
这是我最后想做的事情了
That's the last thing I ever wanted to do.
我确信这不是你想做的  但是事情就是这样
I know that's not what you wanna do, but that's just the way that it is.
难道你不在意别人是怎么想的吗？难道你不在意…
Don't you care what people think? Doesrt it bother you that people...
…别人把你当笑话？而我也不幸成了这笑话的一部分？
...are making you out to be a joke and that I'll be included in that?
你认为那是对的？是吗？
Do you think that's right? Do you?
你也许不会相信  但是你出生时才这么大
You ain't gonna believe this, but you used to fit right here.
我把你举起来  对你母亲说
I'd hold you up and say to your mother:
"这孩子会成为世界上最棒的小孩"
"This kid is gonna be the best kid in the world.
"这孩子会成为史无前例的人"
This kid is gonna be somebody better than anybody ever knew."
你长大了  很好  很美妙
And you grew up good and wonderful.
看着你长大  每天都是恩惠
It was great just watching, every day was like a privilege.
然后就是你自己奋斗的人生了  自己去承担自己的事情
Then the time come for you to be your own man and take on the world...
你也确实做得很好  但是有些时候  你变了
...and you did. But somewhere along the line, you changed.
你不再是你
You stopped being you.
你让别人指着你的脸  说你不好
You let people stick a finger in your face and tell you you're no good.
而且当遇上不顺心的事时  你开始怪罪于其他事物
And when things got hard, you started looking for something to blame...
比如说巨大的阴影
...like a big shadow.
让我告诉你一些你已经知道的事
Let me tell you something you already know.
这世界不完全都是阳光和彩虹
The world ain't all sunshine and rainbows.
这是一个非常卑鄙险恶的世界  我不在乎你是多么坚强
It's a very mean and nasty place, and I don't care how tough you are...
如果你屈服的话  它会把你永远打趴下的
...it will beat you to your knees and keep you there if you let it.
你  我  没人能够  击打得比生活还重
You, me or nobody is gonna hit as hard as life.
但是这不在于你击打的多重  而在于你能被击打的多重…
But it ain't about how hard you hit. It's about how hard you can get hit...
…但却能继续向前
...and keep moving forward.
你能怎么承受  并且继续前进
How much you can take and keep moving forward.
这才是真正的胜利！
That's how winning is done!
如果你知道你自己的价值  那么就前进  去实现你的价值
If you know what you're won'th, go and get what you're won'th.
但是你必须乐意承受挨打  而不是没能实现目标时…
But you gotta be willing to take the hits, and not pointing fingers...
…却指着别人说  是因为他或她的原因！
...saying you ain't where you wanna be because of him or her or anybody!
懦夫才会那么做  你不是！你远比那个出色
Cowards do that, and that ain't you! You're better than that!
无论怎样我都爱你
I'm always gonna love you no matter what.
无论发生什么我都爱你
No matter what happens.
你是我的儿子  我的骨肉
You're my son and you're my blood.
你是我生命中最美好的事物
You're the best thing in my life.
但是只有当你开始相信自己时  你才拥有真正的人生
But until you start believing in yourself, you ain't gonna have a life.
别忘了多去看看你母亲
Don't forget to visit your mother.
- 那些花很美  - 是啊
- Yeah, those are beautiful.  - Yeah.
- 今天你早下班了？- 没有
- You get off early from work?  - No.
我离开了
I left.
我辞职了
I quit.
辞职？为什么？
Quit, why?
我不是很…
I wasrt very...
我不知道  我只是… 我不适合那里
I don't know, I just... I didn't fit in there.
我懂
I understand.
- 那你打算干吗？- 现在？
- So, what are you gonna do?  - Right now?
现在我宁愿和你呆在一起
Right now I'd rather be with you.
可以吗？
Is that all right?
当然
Yeah.
我已经好久没有看过拳赛了
It's been a long time since I seen a fight.
关于拳击的东西  你都知道
You know all there is to know about fighting...
所以我们也没必要讲那些老套路了
...so there's no sense us going down that same old road again.
要打败这个家伙  你需要速度  但是你没有
To beat this guy, you need speed. You don't have it.
而且你的膝盖受不了重击  所以大范围跑动是不可能的
And your knees can't take the pounding, so hard running is out.
你脖子还有关节炎  而且你的很多关节都有骨质增生
And you got arthritis in your neck. And you've got calcium deposits...
所以快速轻拳也不可能
...on most of your joints, so sparring is out.
我有那毛病
I had that problem.
所以我们能依靠的就是  出色的老式钝拳创伤
So what we'll be calling on is good old-fashioned blunt-force trauma.
大马力的  超重型的  铸铁般的  打桩机一样的重拳
Horsepower. Heavy-duty, cast-iron, pile-driving punches...
会让他疼得要命  这些重拳可以打得他直喊爹娘
...that will have to hurt so much they'll rattle his ancestors.
每次你击打他
Every time you hit him with a shot...
他就是感觉象在亲吻特快列车
...it's gotta feel like he tried kissing the express train.
好！让我们来制造一些重伤炸弹吧
Yeah! Let's start building some hurting bombs.
- 你可以  - 你能行 洛奇！
- Yeah, you'll get it.  - You can do it, Rocko!
变得更强壮！
Getting stronger!
- 用力！用力！用力！- 加油！
- Up! Up! Up!  - Come on!
加油！
Go!
- 好！- 好！好！
- Yeah!  - Yeah! Yeah!
加油  洛奇！
Come on, Rocko!
加油  加油  打它们  打它们
Come on. Come on. Let's hit them. Hit them.
你能行  洛奇
You can do it, Rock.
变得更强壮！
Getting stronger!
- 用力！用力！用力！- 加油！加油！
- Up, up, up!  - Go! Go!
好极了！
All right!
好！好！
Yeah! Yeah!
耶！
Yeah!
洛奇·巴尔博亚  217磅！
Rocky Balboa, 217!
实力派重量级拳王  梅森·迪克逊  221磅！
The undisputed heavyweight champion, Mason Dixon, 221!
非常感谢  我很感激  拳王  谢谢
Thank you very much. I appreciate it, champ. Thanks a lot.
洛奇！洛奇！洛奇！
Rocky! Rocky! Rocky!
- 知道这里蕴含着多少钱吗？- 很多
- Know how much money is in this?  - A lot of it.
想象一下清空这个地方
Imagine trying to clean this place.
- 不 我是认真的  - 巴尔博亚！
- No, seriously.  - Balboa!
你们先走  我等会儿来找你们
You guys, I'll catch up with you all later, okay?
罗伯特  你跟我一起吧？
Robert, why don't you hang with me?
- 你好吗？拳王  - 很好
- How you doing, champ?  - I'm good.
我们两个都没必要在这场比赛中受伤
No reason for neither one of us to get hurt in this fight.
我会尽量照顾好你  保证不让你丢脸
I'll do my best to carry you, make sure you save face.
不会让你难堪的
There'd be no embarrassment.
但是我保证  如果你跟来真的  你重击我  弄疼我
But I promise you, you try to press me, you hit me, you hurt me...
打我腰带以下或是暗算我  我肯定把你打翻
...you hit me low, cheap-shot me, I'll get you out of there.
你知道  很多人来拉斯维加斯都是失败告终  我不是
You know, a lot of people come to Vegas to lose. I didn't.
已经结束了
It's already over.
一切只有在结束的时候才会结束
Ain't nothing over till it's over.
那是什么时候的事？80 年代？
What's that from, the '80s?
也许是 70 年代
That's probably the '70s.
记住我说的
Just remember what I said.
嘿  拳王
Hey, yo, champ.
你没有一点害怕吗？
Yo, ain't you a little scared?
我没什么怕的
I don't get scared.
我认为  当你害怕的时候会更努力一点的
I think you try a little harder when you're scared.
我过去就是这样  很奏效
This is what has worked for me.
- 我不怕  - 哦 是啊 你不怕我？
- I ain't scared.  - Oh, yeah. You ain't scared of me?
快点  给我露两手  快点
Come on, let's see what you got. Come on.
嘿  不要击打我  现在我很脆弱
Hey, don't hit me, I'm brittle.
- 嘿  - 嗨
- Hey.  - Hi.
- 你还好吗？- 我只是在思考
- How you doing?  - I was just thinking.
- 你要进来吗？- 不了 不了 这样可以
- Did you wanna come in?  - No, no, no, it's okay.
我只是想要…
I just wanted to...
说不清楚  只是想过来  祝你明天好运
...I dor t know, come by and wish you good luck for tomorrow.
- 谢谢  - 嗯
- Thanks.  - Yeah.
我给你带了些东西
I brought you something.
我希望你不要介意  我从餐馆里拿的
I hope you don't mind, I took it from the restaurant.
- 没关系  - 谢谢
- No.  - Thanks.
艾黛丽安
Adrian.
是啊  我想她会保佑你平安的
Yeah. Thought she would keep you safe.
是啊  是啊  她过去总是给我带来好运
Yeah. Yeah, she always brought me luck.
嗯
Yeah.
我想感谢你为我和我孩子做的一切
I wanted to say thanks for everything you've done for me and my kid.
你一直很出色…
You've been great and...
你知道  明天…
You know, tomorrow...
你将去证明最后一件事  你的心里一直有着一个人
...you're gonna prove that the last thing to age on somebody is their heart.
- 我会努力的  - 证明给他们看吧
- I'll try.  - You go show them.
谢谢你
Thank you.
重量级拳王一直是…
The heavyweight championship has been...
…这 120 年来体育界最垂涎的头衔
...one of sports' most coveted titles for 120 years.
两次重量级拳王  洛奇·巴尔博亚
Two-time heavyweight champion Rocky Balboa...
费城重击者  以他铸铁般的下巴…
...the Philadelphia slugger, renowned for his cast-iron jaw...
凶猛的身体攻击  和钢铁般的意志而闻名
...ferocious body attack and will of steel...
在过去对阵身体比他强壮的那些对手中
...all of which have carried the smaller fighter to victories...
所有这些都给他带来了一次次胜利
...over the years against physically superior opponents.
梅森·迪克逊  现任重量级拳王头衔拥有者
And Mason Dixon, the current heavyweight title holder...
集合了任何一名拳手都想有的  速度、决心、信心于一身
...with all the speed, determination and confidence any fighter could want.
但是很多人仍然质疑  他是否真的拥有一颗拳王的心
But many still question whether he has the heart of a true champion...
他从没受到过真正的挑战  今晚  我们将拭目以待
...never having been pushed to go the distance. Tonight, we find out.
这里是拉斯维加斯的曼德勒海湾竞技中心
Here at the Mandalay Bay Event Center in Las Vegas...
万众期待的巅峰之战
...for the much-anticipated showdown...
"战列步兵" 梅森·迪克逊
...between Mason "The Line" Dixon...
对阵洛奇 "意大利种马" 巴尔博亚
...and Rocky "The Italian Stallion" Balboa.
大家好  我是吉姆·兰普利
Hello, I'm Jim Lampley
我现在和拉里·莫辛特  马克思·科莱曼
with Larry Merchant and Max Kellerman...
在拉斯维加斯的曼德勒海湾酒店向你现场直播…
...live from the Mandalay Bay Hotel in Las Vegas, where we anticipate...
拳击史上最不寻常的  最令人注目的一场比赛
...one of the most outrageous and compelling events in boxing history.
现任不被认同的重量级拳王 "战列步兵" 梅森·迪克逊
The unappreciated heavyweight champion, Mason "The Line" Dixon...
冒险以名誉为赌注
...putting his reputation on the line...
对阵传奇人物  前前前一任拳王洛奇·巴尔博亚
...against legendary ex-champion, Rocky Balboa.
尽管多数人美其名曰这是一场荣耀的训练赛
Even though most see this as more of a glorified sparring session...
但是场中气氛仍很热烈
...the energy in the room is electric.
拉里  为什么这场比赛被定义为表演赛？
Larry, why is this billed as an exhibition?
我乱猜  他们总不能说这是一场行刑赛吧
Wild guess: So they wouldn't have to call it an execution.
撒迦利亚书 4 章 6 节写道 "不是靠力量  不是靠势力"
Zacariah 4:6 says, "It is not by strength, not by might...
"而是靠灵魂  在耶稣之下…"
...but by his spirit we have already claimed the victory...
"我们已经宣称了胜利"
...in our Lord Jesus Christ."
好运  洛奇
Good luck, Rocky.
谢谢  斯柏德  我很感激
Thanks, Spider. Appreciate it.
没有人会对他抱太大的希望…
Nobody's expecting much, I think, from the way-past-his-prime...
年老势衰的洛奇·巴尔博亚
...former champ, Rocky Balboa.
洛奇  我有话对你说
Rock, I gotta talk to you.
听着  我知道你有很多心事  你必须要全部宣泄出来
Look, I know you got a lot of stuff you gotta get out of your system.
今晚你就宣泄出来  知道吗？放那头野兽出笼
Tonight you do it. Right? Get rid of the damn beast...
放手一搏  一劳永逸  加油  我爱你
...let it be done, once and for all. Please, I love you.
洛奇！洛奇！洛奇！
Rocky! Rocky! Rocky!
场内灯光关闭了  观众们的情绪越来越高涨
There go the lights. The buzz is building toward a roaring crescendo.
那歌是哪里来的？
Where did that come from?
我告诉过你  我喜欢辛纳塔
I told you. I love Sinatra.
他很不错  辛纳塔
He's very good, Sinatra.
- 走吧  - 很好
- Let's go.  - Very good.
首先出场的是洛奇·巴尔博亚  沙场老将
And here comes Rocky Balboa, veteran of the wars...
最后的表演
...here for one more last hurrah.
也许是最后的晚餐  而他正是主菜
Or the Last Supper, perhaps, with him as the main course.
这是什么音乐？不会吧
What's that music? You can't be serious.
"远大理想"？讲述的是痴心妄想吧
"High Hopes"? Talk about wishful thinking.
然而也许没理想会更加现实  无论怎样  观众喜欢这样
Well, maybe no hopes is more realistic. Anyway, the crowd likes it.
看看"意大利种马"  很酷很放松
Look at the Italian Stallion. Cool and relaxed.
洛奇只是过期的失败者  观众们根本不在乎他
Rocky's an off-the-board underdog, and they don't care at all.
这关系到他的骄傲和尊严  还有他的拳头  朋友们
This is about his pride and dignity and his punch, guys.
拳手最后的东西就是他的拳头
The last thing to go is a guy's punch.
洛奇总会有拳手的机会
Rocky always has that puncher's chance.
听得出来  洛奇·巴尔博亚仍然是观众心目中的冠军
Rocky Balboa is still, as you can hear, the people's champion.
以我预测  至少前两个回合
Prediction, guys: For at least two rounds...
迪克逊要有的忙了
...Dixors gonna have his hands full.
只是两个回合？你现在未免也太乐观了吧
Two whole rounds? We have a cockeyed optimist in the house.
- 你好吗？- 观众们想看到…
- How you doing?  - The crowd wants to see...
…真实的比赛  或者至少是…
...something real, or at least...
洛奇·巴尔博亚刚刚向我问好了
Rocky Balboa just asked me how I'm doing.
我可是看着他的拳赛长大的
I grew up watching this guy.
我从没想过我能直播他的拳赛
I never thought I'd be calling one of his fights.
太不可思议了  我可是他的拳迷  有点情不自禁
This is unbelievable. I'm a fan, I can't help it.
现在出场的是梅森·迪克逊
Now here comes Mason Dixon.
梅森·迪克逊走上了拳台
Mason Dixon establishing his presence in the ring.
拳台下突然有人跟他对话
And suddenly now a conversation breaking out at ringside.
迈克·泰森正在呼喊 "战列步兵" 梅森·迪克逊的名字
Mike Tyson calling out Mason "The Line" Dixon.
这里没你的事  我才是拳王
You can't call no shots here. I'm the champ.
你干不出什么的  这只是慈善表演
You not doing nothing. This is charity work.
你居然和那个老骨头打
You got that midget with you right there.
女士们  先生们  欢迎来到赌城拉斯维加斯的…
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to the Mandalay Bay...
…曼德勒海湾度假胜地
...resort and casino of Las Vegas.
今晚最特别的一场比赛…
And a special main event of the evening...
十回合的重量级拳赛
...10 rounds of heavyweight excitement...
内华达州竞技委员会批准的赛事
...sanctioned by the Nevada State Athletic Commission.
本场比赛的裁判是乔·科泰斯
And when the bell rings, the referee in charge of the action, Joe Cortez.
现在  在场的成千观众和…
And now, for the thousands in attendance...
…上百万的电视机前的观众  先生们女士们
...and the millions watching around the world, ladies and gentlemen...
让我们准备尖叫吧！
...let's get ready to rumble!
首先介绍的是蓝角的…
Introducing first, fighting out of the blue corner...
穿着金黑色短裤的  官方称重 217 磅
...wearing black with gold, official weight, 217 pounds.
他的职业纪录为 57 胜 54 次击倒对手获胜
His professional record, 57 victories including 54 knockouts...
23 败 1 次平局
...with 23 defeats and one draw.
他是费城的拳击骄傲
He is the fighting pride of Philadelphia...
两次世界重量级拳王
...the two-time heavyweight champion of the world...
"意大利种马"
..."The Italian Stallion"...
洛奇…
...R ocky...
巴尔博亚！
...Balboa!
真希望他被打爆头
Hope he gets his head busted.
闭嘴
Shut up.
拳台对面红角的…
Across the ring, fighting out of the red corner...
穿着蓝白色短裤的  官方称重 221 磅
...wearing white with blue, official weight, 221 pounds.
有着完美的职业纪录  33 战 33 胜
He has a perfect professional record, consisting of 33 bouts...
30 次击倒对手获胜
...33 victories, including 30 knockouts.
出生于佛罗里达的坦帕
Originally from Tampa, florida...
现在在内华达的拉斯维加斯打拳
...but now fighting out of Las Vegas, Nevada...
无可置疑的统治者  无敌的
...the reigning undisputed, undefeated...
世界重量级拳王
...heavyweight champion of the world...
"战列步兵"
...Mason "The Line"...
梅森·迪克逊！
...Dixon!
好  先生们
All right, gentlemen.
好  梅森  洛奇  在更衣室我们都强调过规则了
All right, Mason, Rocky. We went over the rules in the dressing room.
我希望这是场出色干净的比赛  注意肾部攻击  后颈部攻击…
I expect a good, clean fight. Watch the kidney punches, rabbit punches...
腰带以下的攻击  小心这些  希望你们能展示良好的体育风范
...Iow blows, be careful with those. Give me good sportsmanlike conduct.
记住  先生们  我很公平但我很严格  碰拳套！
Remember, gentlemen, I'm fair but I'm firm. Touch them up!
- 好好享受这比赛  - 拳王的状态现在不是最好
- Enjoy the ride.  - The champ is not in the best shape...
也许他打算尽快拿下比赛早点回家
...we've seen him in. Maybe he plans to phone this in and go home early.
- 那也不足为奇  - 我爱你 孩子 很高兴你做到了
- That wouldn't be a surprise.  - Glad you could make it.
关于洛奇  我们所知道的有一点是肯定的
One thing about Rocky we know for sure:
这家伙状态不错
This guy's showing up in shape.
- 这老家伙一定是疯了  - 他不疯不行 他已经在这里了
- The old mars crazy.  - He's gotta be crazy. He's in here.
- 好的  - 慢慢来 这只是场表演赛
- Okay.  - Take it easy. This is an exhibition.
知道？击倒他
All right? Do it to him.
你一定要在三局里调整好步伐  每次你击打他后  都后退
You got three rounds to set a pace. Every time you hit him, make a dent.
- 懂了  - 现在是洛奇·巴尔博亚比赛的前一刻
- Got it.  - The moments before...
我不敢相信这真的发生了！
...a Rocky Balboa fight? I can't believe it's here!
第一回合开始了
Round one begins.
如果老乔治·福尔曼  可以一拳震惊这个世界
If old George foreman shocked the world with one punch...
那为什么老洛奇·巴尔博亚就不可以？
...why can't old Rocky Balboa?
赛场内除了兴奋之外
And as much excitement as there is in the arena...
同样也有种不详的预感
...there's a sense of foreboding as well.
现在  梅森开始用他的刺拳开始攻击
And now, Mason "The Line" Dixon goes to work with his jab as though...
尽管他的对手是  重量级领域里的头号挑战者
...he's fighting against the number one challenger in the heavyweight division.
看  这就是人们预测到会早早上演的
See, this is to be expected early on.
早知道拳王会  用他的刺拳来压制距离…
You knew the champ would control the distance with his jab...
…压制他的身高和他的臂展
...his height, his range.
巴尔博亚找机会进行了一次攻击  但是完全打偏了
Balboa looking to get in a shot, misses wildly.
你喜欢吧？
Did you like that?
比赛就象是  一个速度沙袋对阵一个击打沙袋
It looks like a speed bag against a punching bag.
洛奇开始显出疲态  可以理解
Rocky's understandably frustrated...
但是他复出来参加这场比赛
...but he came out of retirement to get into a fight.
洛奇的拥护者不想被愚弄
Guys named Rocky don't like to be toyed with.
一拳就可以扭转局势
One punch could still turn it around.
显然他今天早上忘了  吃他的关节炎药了
Apparently he forgot his arthritis meds this morning.
洛奇没击中
Rocky misses.
就像飞弹一样  拳王给对手下巴来了一拳
There's a meat-seeking missile on the point of the chin by the champ.
- 迪克逊还是更多的刺拳  - 洛奇！洛奇！洛奇！
- More pinpoint jabs by Dixon.  - Rocky! Rocky! Rocky!
巴尔博亚一记右手重拳  又一记左拳  又一记右拳！
And there's a hard right hand and a left and a right by Balboa!
他一连串的攻击把迪克逊逼到了绳圈处！
He drives Dixon into the ropes with a series of shots!
观众沸腾了！
And the crowd goes berserk!
迪克逊用一系列攻击来还击巴尔博亚
Dixon punishing Balboa for the temerity of landing those shots.
双方在绳角处对峙  都放开了打
It's toe to toe in the corner. Balboa and Dixon letting it all go.
巴尔博亚用组合拳  有效的攻击拳王的头部
Balboa landing potent combinations to the head of the champion.
第一回合结束  铃响得很及时对迪克逊来说
A wake-up call for Dixon.
- 你还好吗？- 我很好
- You all right?  - Yeah, I'm all right.
- 这老家伙拳套里有砖头  - 你心里的那些闷事呢？
- The mars got bricks in his gloves.  - Where's the stuff in the basement?
- 还在  - 他是来认真比赛的 知道吗？
- It's still there.  - He came to battle, okay?
- 想击倒我  - 听我说
- Trying to knock me out.  - Listen.
如果他一有机会  他肯定会把你的骨头打断的
If there's a bone he can break, he's gonna do it.
- 尊重你的对手  - 那我的自尊呢？
- Give the man respect.  - What about my respect?
记分系统的比分简直神奇
CompuBox numbers tell the grisly story here.
这回合巴尔博亚 13 次出拳 9 次击中
Balboa landed nine of 13 punches in that round.
迪克逊不可思议的 69 次出拳 59 次击中
Dixon landed an incredible 59 out of 69.
- 你为什么不听我？- 洛奇来过这里无数次了
- Why don't you listen to me?  - Rocky's been here a million times.
在经过被动的一回合后  第二回合就要开始了
Coming out to start a round after he took a beating in the previous one.
- 记住我说的 知道吗？- 我警告过他 我警告过他
- Remember what I said, okay?  - I warned him. I warned him.
他累了  他的腿会更快或是已经不行了
He's tired. His legs are going fast, or already gone.
然而真正非凡的就是无论怎样  洛奇还是在继续着
And what's truly extraordinary is that Rocky can still take it.
因发给洛奇拳击执照  而受批评的拳击委员会…
The boxing commission, which was criticized for licensing him...
…肯定会受到攻击  如果洛奇不幸发生了意外
...would be massacred if something happened to Rocky.
好一记左直拳！洛奇倒下了！
And a monstrous straight left hand! Down goes Rocky!
比赛可能就要以令人信服的结果收场！
And that could conceivably be the end of the fight!
表演赛到此为止  但是没有  巴尔博亚起来了
That could be the exhibition right there. But no. Balboa up.
裁判科泰斯问他是否要继续比赛  洛奇说继续
Referee Joe Cortez asks if he wants to continue, and Rocky says yes.
就算是洛奇·巴尔博亚  这也未免太勇敢了
Even Rocky Balboa could be too brave for his own good.
迪克逊迅速回来想就此结束比赛
Dixon comes right back to try to finish it.
巴尔博亚差点又被打倒了！
Balboa almost went down!
洛奇用力把迪克逊推开
Rocky actually shoves Dixon back.
而迪克逊出拳更加凶狠
As Dixon lands these brutal shots.
- 防守！防守！- 近距离的攻击
- Cover up! Cover up!  - Open shots at close range.
右拳  左拳  巴尔博亚倒下了！
Right and left hands, and down goes Balboa!
这也许是他拳击生涯的最后一次了！
Perhaps for the last time in his fighting career!
- 差不多了  - 三！四！
- That should do it.  - Three! Four!
五！六！
Five! Six!
- 起来！起来！- 七！
Get up! Get up!  - Seven!
八！九！
Eight! Nine!
- 感觉怎样 先生？还好吗？- 现在洛奇发火了
- How do you feel, man? You okay?  - Now Rocky is furious with himself.
他说服科泰斯他要继续比赛
He convinces Cortez he wants to keep fighting.
迪克逊要裁判终止比赛
Dixors pointing at the ref to end it.
洛奇挥动他的手臂  说他没事
Rocky waving his arms and saying he's fine.
- 他想继续！- 放开打！放开打！
- He wants to go on!  - Let it go! Let it go!
巴尔博亚回来了！左右拳交替…
And Balboa comes back! With a left and a right...
第二次把迪克逊逼到了绳圈处！
...and bulls Dixon into the ropes for the second round in a row!
迪克逊用有力的一连串左拳还击
Back comes Dixon with brutal left-hand shots.
- 迪克逊弄伤了手！- 追击他！
- Dixon hurt his hand there!  - Go after him!
这可是洛奇的大好机会！
This is Rocky's best chance!
很显然拳王在击打洛奇时  弄伤了自己的手！
The champ obviously hurt his hand on Rocky's hip!
巴尔博亚立即采取了行动  有力的右勾拳！
And Balboa immediately going to work to the body! Huge right hook!
巴尔博亚连续攻击迪克逊的身体！都是些重拳
Balboa ripping away at Dixors body! These are big punches.
洛奇！洛奇！洛奇！
Rocky! Rocky! Rocky!
好样的！
Yes!
洛奇·巴尔博亚击倒了现任的重量级拳王！
Rocky Balboa has knocked the reigning heavyweight champion down!
- 打他！- "战列步兵" 梅森·迪克逊…
- You hurt him!  - Mason "The Line" Dixon...
…在他整个职业生涯中…
...has never taken this kind of punishment...
…从没受到过这样的屈辱！
...in his entire professional career!
或许他的头部还没中拳  但他的肋骨在重击之下都快碎了
Maybe he's clearing his head, but the body shots really caved in his ribs.
巴尔博亚想着要击倒对手！
Balboa is thinking knockout himself!
巴尔博亚又一记反勾拳  又是两下！
Another counterhook by Balboa, followed by two more!
迪克逊开始用自己的勾拳还击！现在洛奇有点被打晕了
Dixon fires back his own hooks! Now Rocky's stunned.
在绳圈处两人展开了殊死搏斗
It's an all-out war along the ropes...
第二回合两人难分高低  在拳台上引起了一阵巨大的骚动！
...as round two comes to a close amid a giant tumult in the ring!
难以置信
Incredible.
好！
All right!
欢迎来到洛奇的天地
Welcome to Rockyland.
- 手怎么样了？- 我的手断了
- How's the hand?  - My hand's broken.
如果我们输了  你就完蛋了！
We lose, it's your ass! Your ass!
等会儿手会麻木的
It will numb up on you in a few rounds.
手麻木后  迪克逊就可以用力出拳了
Once that hand numbs up, Dixon will be able to throw it hard.
但在那之前  是洛奇的机会
Until then, here is Rocky's chance.
- 没有退路了  - 挺住！拳王
- No reverse!  - Take the pain, champ.
保持状态  每个人都以为这是场笑话  包括我！
Stay on him! Everybody thought this was a joke, including me!
但是现在没人会嘲笑了！保持状态！打倒他！
Now nobody's laughing! Stay on him! You go get him!
变得更强壮！
Go out strong!
不要让他靠近！
Keep him off you!
就是那样！就是那样！
That's it! That's it!
你赢了刚才那个回合  放倒他
You won that round. Break him down.
打他！打他！
Bomb him! Bomb him!
好！
Yeah!
继续用力击打他！
Just keep throwing them bombs!
加油！
Come on.
你能做到
You can do this.
洛奇！洛奇！
Rocko. Rocko.
好  加油  打他！
Yeah, come on, go!
打倒他！放倒他！
Go through him! Run over him!
摆脱他！
Unload on him!
闪开  梅森！
Get down, Mason!
双方都使出浑身解数
They're leaving nothing on the table, guys.
拳迷们仍然都站着  也许他们一个礼拜都坐不下来
The fans are still standing. They may not be able to sit down for a week.
- 你做得很好！- 我比我想象的要做得好
- You're doing great!  - I'm doing better than I thought.
- 你肯定他没事？- 我有过更糟糕的
- You sure he's okay?  - I've had worse.
最后一个回合的对峙  谁会想到有这个结果？
Toe to toe, one round to go. Who would've believed this was possible?
- 这个眼睛能看得见吗？- 让我跟他谈
- Can you see out of that eye?  - Let me talk to him.
如果不行的话  就没必要再继续下去了
Don't take any more chances than you have to.
没必要证明更多了  爸爸  没必要证明了
There's nothing more to prove, Pop. There's nothing more to prove.
我会用我的方式完成
I gotta go out the way I gotta go out.
你能做到  洛奇！
You can do it, Rocko!
- 打最后一个回合 我们就回家  - 好 那加油
- One more round, we go home.  - Okay, then do it.
有句老话 "每个伟大的拳王…
There's an old saying that every great champion has...
…都有一场伟大的比赛没打"  到目前为止  洛奇正在证明这话
...one great fight left in him, and Rocky is proving it so far.
- 快点 碰拳套  - 洛奇 你生命中最后的一回合！
- Come on. Touch them up.  - Rocko! The last round of your life!
- 快点 朋友们  - 最后一回合！
- Come on, guys.  - The last round!
快点  碰拳套  快点  碰一下
Come on. Touch them up, let's go. Touch them up.
- 你是个疯老头  - 你会知道的
- You are one crazy old man.  - You'll get there.
开始
Let's go.
十回合中的最后一回合  谁会想到洛奇·巴尔博亚还仍然…
Tenth round of a scheduled 10. Who would ever have dreamed...
在这场被称为 "表演赛" 的比赛中
...that Rocky Balboa would still be in this quote, "exhibition," against...
- 对抗重量级拳王呢？- 你能行！加油！
...the heavyweight champion?  - You can do it! Come on!
这场拳赛仿佛是  迪克逊在忙着训练一样
This fight is as though Dixon got on-the-job training in courage.
- 防守！防守！- 现在双方都已经感觉不到疼痛了
- Cover up! Cover up!  - They're both in a pain-free zone!
就像是在另一个时空比赛一样！
These guys are fighting in another dimension right now!
难以置信！巴尔博亚径直走向迪克逊的拳头
Beyond belief! Balboa just walking straight into Dixors punches.
就像是给迪克逊训练
Target practice for Dixon.
双方都用右勾拳相互攻击  巴尔博亚没力气了！
They're exchanging right hooks! Balboa's drilled!
迪克逊也没力气了  他连挥拳头的力气都没了！
Here comes Dixon! He's exhausted from just punching the man!
打倒这家伙  梅森！
Knock this bum out, Mase!
你对孩子是怎么说的？不在于你能把对方打得多重
What is it you said to the kid? It ain't about how hard you hit.
而在于你能被击打的多重  但却能继续向前
It' about how hard you can get hit and keep moving forward.
你能承受的多重  但继续前进
How much you can take and keep moving forward.
- 洛奇！洛奇！洛奇！- 起来！
- Rocky! Rocky! Rocky!  - Get up.
- 加油！起来！- 洛奇！洛奇！洛奇！
- Let's go! Get up!  - Rocky! Rocky! Rocky!
洛奇！洛奇！洛奇！
Rocky! Rocky! Rocky!
起来！
Get up.
又一记重拳  洛奇的祖先一定也感觉到了
Another monster body shot. Rocky's ancestors must have felt that one.
加油  洛奇！继续挥拳！
Come on, Rocky! Start moving those hands!
还有两分钟不到了
Less than two minutes to go.
巴尔博亚站起来了  观众们都震惊了
The crowd is astonished that Balboa got up.
- 加油！- 扭转局势 彻底打倒他
- Come on!  - Turn it over! All the way through!
用力还击他！
And retaliates with fury!
把他干倒！
Chop him down!
加油！洛奇！加油！
Come on, Rocky! Come on!
马上放倒他！
Take him out now!
双方又开始一系列的相互攻击！
They're trading shots again!
巴尔博亚有什么打什么！
Balboa is trying to hit anything and anywhere!
拿下！拿下！
Win it! Win it!
好！
Yes!
你是个伟大的拳王  你有这颗心
You're a great champion. You got heart.
谢谢你的比赛  好家伙
Thanks for the opportunity. Good man.
太难以置信了  这是我见过的最伟大的事情
That was unbelievable. That was the greatest thing I've ever seen.
你做到了  这才是你所说的拳击
You did it. That's the kind of fighting you're talking about.
嘿  保利
Hey, Paulie.
那野兽现在走了  野兽走了
That beast is gone now. The beast is out.
体坛最滥用的词就是 "难以置信"
One of the most overused words in sports, guys, is "incredible."
我讨厌这么说  但是这确实难以置信
I hate to say it. This is incredible.
我们走！
Let's go!
女士们先生们  在比分出来之前…
Ladies and gentlemen, before we go to the scorecards...
请为这两位重量级勇士鼓掌！
...a round of applause for these two heavyweight warriors!
裁判产生了点小分歧
We have a split decision.
阿德莱德·博德  95比94
Adelaide Byrd scores it 95-94...
迪克逊获胜
...Dixon.
查克·赞帕  95比94
Chuck Giampa has it 95-94...
巴尔博亚获胜
...Balboa.
比尔·葛拉汉姆  95比94
And Bill Graham scores it 95-94...
决定性的比分
...for the winner by split decision, and still undefeated...
仍然是卫冕的世界重量级拳王…
...the heavyweight champion of the world...
"战列步兵" 梅森·迪克逊获胜！
...Mason "The Line" Dixon!
洛奇！洛奇！洛奇！
Rocky! Rocky! Rocky!
你知道  没有你我做不到
You know, I couldn't have done nothing without you.
艾黛丽安  我们做到了
Yo, Adrian, we did it.
我们做到了
We did it.